yo yo yo how's it going everybody this
is uh techno geek here doing a little
bit of a solo episode today uh me and uh
Justin we woke up we were planning on
recording today and I got a message from
Justin about 30 minutes before and he
was like Yo
dude I'm sick and I was like Yo dude me
too so um I I volunteered as tribute um
I am also feeling a little bit under the
weather I woke up this morning uh I
don't know if it was pollen or jet lag
or hopefully not Co or something but um
yeah it's uh it's definitely I'm feeling
a little funky today and you can
probably hear it in my voice so I'm G to
try and do a little bit of a solo
episode here I did want to talk about a
couple things um and uh yeah we'll uh
we'll see if if this one uh ends up
making it out of the editing Bay so um
for those of you who don't know I've
actually been uh dealing with some um
some hacking motivation uh stuff lately
it's been pretty difficult for me to
find you know the time and the
motivation and um sort of the energy uh
just with day-to-day stuff um having a
full-time job and all that kind of stuff
to to want to hack and and be able to
find a Target that I can really focus in
on and and enjoy hacking um but I was
able to sort of break that curse a
little bit recently which was awesome um
I you know while I was on vacation I
sort of got a little bit of a refresher
it was nice to um sort of clear my head
and and be able to sit down and and
focus again um and so I I sort of just
picked a Target that I was interested in
that I've been keeping an eye on for a
while they happen to me R running a
promotion on hacker one as well so that
was sort of just like good timing I was
like that looks interesting uh let me
just take a little bit of a deep dive
and I just started poking and um you
know things things went really well um I
found a lot of really interesting
gadgets and um I just wanted to sort of
talk about um you know how you can break
that funk for yourself and I think for
me probably the biggest thing that I was
able to do was to just sort of ignore um
all of you know what was going on in my
head and really just return back to my
roots um in terms of like hacking U
methodology and procedure and um all
that kind of stuff um you know for for
me I think it was difficult to um figure
out where to want to spend my time and
focus on again and I I just sort of was
like you know what let's keep it simple
let's go to Eon let's just find some
assets let's see what looks interesting
and just poke poke poke until there's
nothing to poke at anymore um and just
take lots of notes and find gadgets and
start to piece stuff together start to
piece um how different parts of the
application work um what sort of
acronyms and definitions and
architecture that they're using um how
they route between things what sort of
protection mechanisms they might have in
place um and you know that was perfect
for me you know I was sort of able to
just um hone in a little bit um I found
a lot of really interesting things and
um I got to a point where I felt a
little bit stuck and I reached out to
Justin and I was like hey man here's
like some interesting functionality I
had and I just sort of brain dumped a
lot of the things that I had noticed a
lot of the things that I had been
observing and a lot of the sort of
potential you know 99% um almost there
type of things that I had had and
immediately you know I was he was able
to bounce stuff back and be like hey
here's an xss here's a you know csrf
like all these awesome things so I think
a combination of having that deep dive
having the knowledge feeling like you um
are sort of at at a really like Far
Point in understanding where the
application is how it works and then
having somebody that you can bounce
stuff off of whether that's um in the
critical thinkers chat in the Discord or
um you know a mentor that you might have
or somebody who you like to hack and
collab with um you know I think those
types of resources are really excellent
for finishing your bug or getting new
ideas and helping unblock yourself um
because it's easy to sort of run through
the same ideas over and over again in
your head and be like H what about this
so I've already tried that what about
this so I've already tried that um and
just you know having having those
resources available um of you know
people other hackers other you know
information other exploit attack vectors
um reading through those blog posts all
that kind of stuff I think it's really
really important to just have those
things in your back pocket so that when
you do get stuck or when you do find an
almost bug that you can actually you
know continue to push forward or or have
some sort of um you know path that you
can take to try and take that all the
way to a full bug
um yeah so I just wanted to you know
share a little bit about that um you
know you're not alone if uh if you're
feeling like uh you're stuck you can't
find the motivation to hack um you know
I think what I'd recommend is just sort
of do a brain reset and just you know
ignore all of the you know whatever's
going on whether it's a lack of
motivation or something um just the the
first step to anything is taking the
step right you got to lift your foot um
and so I think uh you know it's always
really difficult to get yourself to do
that um for me I think a good analogy
was um you know like writing a paper I I
hate writing um and like writing is just
not not my thing um but writing can be
easy once you get started um you know it
tends to be that it's more just the
whole concept of having to write
something or long form writing um can be
very intimidating or very um you know
you you see it as like an elephant um
but you got to eat you know one bite at
a time right um how do you run a
marathon one step at a time same thing
so I think just sort of taking that
first step and letting yourself you know
Zone in um and ignore all of the you
know what's the large picture here like
what about finding the rce or the you
know the account takeover or whatever
just you know take the first step um
just open burp open
kaido open the application start
proxying it just start poking at
requests create an account log in just
explore um just start there and uh you
know your I think your Natural Curiosity
really help take over and uh make it
easier to continue and the more routes
that you discover the more things that
you see within the application as
potential bugs or potential attack
vectors um the more options you're going
to have when you come back to it the
next day and go all right what do I look
at next on this target um I think you
know keeping those notes keeping those
open paths keeping those um those
potential attack vectors and those
potential bugs in the back of your head
are really good for motivating you
motivating you to come back to the
application and having things to look at
instead of just coming back to it the
next day and having to basically start
over again um I think this is something
that fron had talked about as well
during our episode with him which was
that some of the best hacking is when he
goes to sleep right before he feels like
he's about to exploit something so that
the next day he's like itching to you
know go and hack on that finish that bug
um and I think that's a really really
positive um way to sort of encourage
yourself and motivate yourself to to
keep hacking and keep coming back to it
um so yeah I just wanted to share a
little bit about that um the other thing
I want to talk about a little bit um
Ambassador World Cup is going on um
looks like uh it's a pretty good
competition so far I know a lot of stuff
is still in triage a lot of stuff is
still sort of getting the severities
figured out um it seems to be a pretty
tight rate race right now I'm not
exactly sure who's winning yet so I
don't want to um I don't want to make a
final call yet but um yeah I uh I
personally haven't been able to do a ton
of hacking on that um as I was on
vacation and I was just dealing with um
some other stuff I had a a wedding to go
to and all sorts of things so um but uh
you know I've been looking at the
American teams and uh they're they're
killing it it's it's awesome to see uh
all my buddies finding really cool bugs
on these targets so um you know I'm
hoping that uh we'll be able to push
through into the next round and I'll be
able to contribute a little bit more but
um yeah it's pretty awesome I know
Justin found some cool stuff there and
uh that that should be really really
interesting um yeah so one other thing I
wanted to shout out was uh that on June
14th uh this Friday we're going to be
doing a another Master Class
specifically for the critical thinkers
uh I'm going to be running this one it's
going to be specifically focused on
mobile hacking and SSL pinning so I know
a lot of people when they're hacking on
mobile apps or they're trying to you
know find endpoints within uh a mobile
app one of the big things that you come
across all the time is certificate
pinning SSL pinning um and that can be a
real big challenge especially when it's
implemented in some custom or bespoke
way um so this master class is really
going to be focused on how to analyze
that how to get around those specific
weird edge cases how to sort of Trace um
where the pinning might be happening how
to track down um within the app within
the aisc how things are working how to
bypass that um and yeah it's going to be
basically focused on everything SS
pinning so if that's something you're
interested in if you're uh either trying
to get into Mobile hacking or you've
been doing some mobile hacking and
really been struggling with the cell
pinning or you've come across some weird
cell pinning cases uh make sure that you
check out the Discord um at ctbb Dosh
showd Discord and uh that'll take you
right to the Discord and we'll uh we'll
have that master class going on Friday
[Music]
[Applause]
all right dude fron we're rolling
welcome to the podcast man thank you so
much thanks for inviting me of course
and and so actually before we jump into
this episode I've got to highlight what
the heck this thing is behind you um
there's like a it looks like it's like a
a framed poster of you with a shell on
Google is that exactly what that is yeah
it is it's it's from 2014 I think 2014
are you kidding me holy crap no yeah
yeah 14 yeah yeah were you born then
dude I was I was I that's the year I
graduated high school actually yeah yeah
no it's uh I think it was from an xxe if
I recall it correctly wow dude that's
nuts so he's just got like Etsy password
on from a Google box on the wall behind
him that's pretty freaking leap all
right guys so as as we often do when we
start off the critical thinking podcast
I'm gonna have to go into Justin story
time a little bit okay so Justin story
time is this I I was at my this the
setting was this Justin was a new a new
bug Bounty Hunter and I had just weasel
my way into my first live hacking event
okay um and I
had I I had I was very nervous I was the
plus one of a plus one and it was
amazing to get to see all of these
hackers that I um you know had respected
for so long uh but there was one guy in
particular you may be able to guess who
that I had not gone and talked to
because I was just too nervous I was too
nervous man I was like there's no way I
can go up and talk to fron Rosen and I
was talking to my wife Mariah and I was
like listen fron is like a legend like I
can't I can't go up and talk to him and
she's like Justin you're at this live
hacking event you have to go up and talk
to him and at that event you had found a
crazy bug um with with uh you know an S3
bucket you know pulling stuff in and
stuff like that um and so I went up and
talked to you and you were so kind to
explain the whole bug to me and just
chat and that was my my first you know
Fanboy moment where I was like wait a
second fron is a real human what's up
that so wow yeah oh that's amazing
that's an awesome story you know
normally they say don't meet your Heroes
but I must say frons you did not
disappoint so that's awesome that's
awesome yeah so there's your little
there's your little flattering intro um
for those of you that don't know frons
um frons is a legend a a hacker a uh a
bug Bounty OG um and dude I'm looking at
this this this plan that we have for
this episode and it's so long I'm not
even sure we're going to be able to get
through all this because there's just so
much good content that you've put out um
so thank you for that but before we get
into all that let's go ahead and talk
about how you got into bug bounty in the
first place because you you got in when
it was really early on the scene and
give us a little career walkthrough that
brought you to the point where you could
do bug Bounty sure I think I mean
initially everything started off as
hiring two young people uh to my company
as Developers and these two young guys
uh Matias Carlson and Fredy K Ruth uh
they were lurking always inside in a
corner in the office doing stuff
together always and and you you didn't
figure like you couldn't really
understand what they were doing but but
when you started talking with them you
realized like they were probably like AR
spoofing the whole office oh my gosh
that's hilarious laughing okay so I'm
I'm going to pause you really quickly
there so you were you at this point you
were already an entrepreneur so you
started you had already started your
company yeah yeah so I can start when
when I was born noid no no so I take us
back yeah exactly take us back no so I I
started as a developer like super early
on and then uh I I built a company
together with the with a business
partner of mine and we hired Frederick
and and Matias and at that time I I
wasn't into hacking I I knew that like
sanitize your inputs that was that was
basically the sure sure the the idea
that I that I knew was was something in
in regards to security uh but this was
very timed also because like this was
200 I think 10 or 11 or something and
and uh I I got curious on what they were
doing and at some point they told us
that they were planning on building like
a company security like a security
company automating security issues so we
were pretty interested in that and we
started talking more deep around like
what would you do what like what is the
product and we kind of realized uh early
on that we could do this together uh
especially because we saw a need for it
in terms of what we were building we
were building like e-commerce websites
and and CMS websites and stuff so we we
then created
detectify and uh and at that point just
when we got started the bug bount scene
uh basically was
initiated so it started with like Milla
and I think it was PayPal and Google and
I think Facebook was early on as well
and then you had you had like like
Russian things as well and and some what
what was it there was something else
also that was like super early on I
think eBay was early on as well like
there was a few of those that that
started uh and and you you basically had
like a a way to do like research on a
huge amount of surface like you could
test a bunch of things on on this attack
surface and so that was very helpful in
like getting to understand what they
were looking for but because now you
didn't have to like hide or simulate
fake things you could literally like
focus on on looking for real bugs so
that got me curious on like what should
I start with and I think they they
basically showed me a bunch of xss
things and and that that's where I like
started off and uh and played like xss
was my you know where I was born sure
and then and then it grew from there U
so I think that was I think it was very
helpful for me to have people next to me
that I could ask and also to to you know
whenever I didn't know anything I could
just ask them and and then I could play
myself and then I could come back and
like get that feedback this is so
awesome because you you you you were in
a position of you know owning this
company or whatever and you hire Maas I
didn't know that that was actually how
you you met
Matias in the first place and then
you're willing you know you're willing
and engaged at a level where you know
you can see like hey what are you doing
and then you start this company with
them and it it just shows this really
you know learner mentality and Matias is
like absolutely you know Matias is Young
at this point right yeah yeah I think
they were they were drop offs from from
the University I think it was like they
were like 18 or 19 if even that wow they
were really young yeah yeah absolutely
and and they they came basically clean
and and like they were they were okay
developers but they were much better
when it come to like security and and
security related things that's when when
they were like shining in terms of
skills yeah D so we felt that like it's
much better for you to like focus on
those things than you know making an
integration with an invoice uh provider
like please stop writing code yeah yeah
yeah no not really like write other code
that is like much more fun to like no
that's that's great I I I've been
meaning to get Matas on the pot as well
so I think I'm going to send him a
message right after this episode because
I'd love to hear his origin story as
well and his side of the situation where
he's like so there's this guy and he
hired me onto this company and then he's
like why are you ARP spoofing the whole
office you know like I love that he's
like he probably has a totally different
story he's like no I wasn't hired
I I into this company show up I didn't
get paid yeah right right
exactly okay so so that that's really
interesting to to hear that that um that
like shift so you were basically just
was doing entirely like software
development when you learned about like
the security side of it what sort of
pequ your interest to like make that
pivot that like really Drew you towards
security because I imagine like if
you're doing a lot of software
development stuff you probably could
have just kept doing that and not made
made a switch into security so what what
was that like draw I think I I think so
I've been like I I was building you know
systems like you you you you say you're
building a system but like what is a
system in in in reality but I was always
like as a developer I always tried to
like oh I can reuse this I need to build
this like modular and and all these
things so I was always curious on how
others were doing it and this was like
I've realized this probably now after
like 14 years but I I kind of know it
like through the whole time but like I'm
I'm super curious on how other people
thought about problems and issues and
I've I've always like I've almost made
it a a challenge to myself to write like
pseudo code of how something is
implemented so I can make a black box a
white box right right uh just because
that's the way I understand how they
thought about things and also that's how
you find that specific little if
statement that they forgot about sure
sure and I think I think that was that
was the point where I realized that I
could do this on other companies and
nobody will like get me into trouble and
I can just you know start poking at them
and see what's what what will happen and
I think that was that was something that
I like I can do this and also get paid
like this was something I was poking at
before you know just figuring out how
stuff worked um and now I could do it
help other companies and also you know
get paid for it yeah so I think that was
that was the trigger to like okay I can
actually gain knowledge by doing this
and also I have like a side effect of I
can actually you know make make money
for it yeah absolutely and and I think
go go ahead no and I think what what
happened in the beginning also when we
started with the bug Bounty was like
those those money came in to our company
so we could fund you know this company
like start these other companies so it
kind of it it was like a very like a
beautiful environment of like we get to
poke on other companies and that creates
other company and it's like it was a
very nice you know circling effect of of
of hunting for bugs and and you see this
a lot with with bug Bounty origin
companies right like in the beginning
when you're trying to like make ends
meat and stuff like that you can even
use bug bounty to fund your own company
right as income into the company so I
think that provides a really nice
launching place for um you know bug
bounty hunters to uh become
entrepreneurs in that
for sure there there are many that that
has like popped up yeah yeah and I've
got I actually was just speaking to
another one this morning who we'll have
on the Pod so there's definitely some
that's one of the things I'm really
interested in is bug Bounty plus
entrepreneurship so we'll definitely
cover more of that later and I've
actually got a section on this dock if
we get through all of it to to pick your
brain a little bit more about that um
but I think you said a really
interesting thing relating to how you
think about hacking which was that you
try to write pseudo code so that you can
kind of understand how the developers
you know would have would have written
this code and turn it you know from a
black box into a white box um and i' I
kind of saw this when we were
collaborating at the last white pack
event we were at um and and you did a
small indicators and that like this
indicator confirms that they've done
something like this because if this
doesn't happen then and and it turns
almost into a like a game where you can
like I'm going to guess what happens if
I do this I'm going to get an error and
I'm like yes I'm getting an error okay
then I know that they've done this and
that yeah exactly like that yeah that
that's that's and I think that's
probably one of the things that makes
you such a good uh exploit exploiter
exploitation you know like I I I don't
know the I don't know the actual word
but um you know someone who's really
able to take an issue and just poke poke
poke poke poke poke poke until you turn
it into a crazy vulnerability um so
that's that's definitely a cool tip for
anybody who has that sort of developer
like brain to kind of you know really be
intentional about theorizing because I
think to some degree we're all doing
this a little bit when we're hacking but
I think if you take it that extra step
and really start thinking in the
Forefront of your brain hey how did they
write this how is this how can I confirm
this you know what little errors might
tell me whether it's this or that um you
you can flesh it out a lot more and it's
the same thing like when when you've
done it with one place and they have
done you know a similar thing somewhere
else yeah then you can like start
comparing them and like okay but it
behaves differently there and like you
can so as soon as you've done that for
like one code block you can see other
implementations in the same company if
they done like you've done a mistake on
one like that that happens a lot like
there's one single thing that that makes
everything break yeah sorry Joel yeah no
no absolutely I mean there's almost like
two different buckets of of this type of
stuff when you're doing testing where um
like the cat
just yeah he he's part of the show too
um yeah but there's almost like two
buckets where like uh you you can
there's like lots of like almost totally
like out left field type of stuff where
you'll test you be like maybe they did
this maybe did that they did that like
you never know maybe maybe they made
this weird mistake like I saw this
somewhere else and then there's the very
like logical approach where you think
about it so sort of basically as if
you're one of the developers or you're
coming from the developers perspective
which is you know you know some of the
technologies that they're using you know
some of the common mistakes that happen
within those languages and those
Technologies and so you can sort of
piece things together can try things
that are a little more targeted towards
like say you're testing you know a Java
application you're going to test stuff
that's similar to spring or you know
you're going to be testing for like Java
specific things instead of like Ruby
issues or JavaScript issues and that
type of testing like it's not to say
that if you test a ruby issue on a Java
stack that like maybe there's something
further down the line that might pop and
the you know but oftentimes having that
context as like a developer is really
really useful because you have that like
that background of like this is
something Weir that they might have done
yeah and I would say one one of the
things you're mentioning there is like
like I don't know why I think people are
talking about it in a different context
but like typing is like one of the most
one of the best things and one of the
worst things in combination that you can
use like that's one of our biggest tools
that we have is is when like for example
when you have PHP you don't have typing
so that's where what you have there is
like then you can start figuring out
where they screwed up and thought it was
an in but it's a string and and in other
languages it's like just because you
have the typing errors you can start
fussing you know variables that didn't
exist because you're getting a typing
error and so like when you think about
it like that's that's one of my best
clues that there's you know that I can
hunt for things is like typing issues uh
or typing errors basically yeah
absolutely and that I feel like that's a
really good transition into one of the
tools that you wrote I when was this
like 2017 or something um this like this
S3 decloaking tool or whatever this
bucket disclosure tool yeah you want to
like talk about that a little bit
because there's you did a whole blog
post and stuff but I feel like yeah I've
got you right yeah the blog post is is
so what happened with that blog post was
like I I had fun bugs that I wanted to
explain but then I realized okay I need
to take one step back like do people
know what this is and like do people
know why this bug happens and do people
know what S3 is and then like do people
know what internet is and like that that
blog post just grew up
no did I lose you yeah yeah I saw that
yeah so it it's looking right now it
says you're 1% uploaded do do you have I
see 1% uploading do do you have so
normally but it goes from one to zero
always yeah so so do you have a a way to
um like make your internet stronger like
are you ethernet it in right now or you
I can I can try I wonder what I have for
uh what I have on my phone instead
because it's it's weird because it
says oh wow
maybe could I've have been the stupid
person in the
room what did you what did you
do I don't want to
say is he he's got proxy on right
now I turned it
off I now he's at 9% uploaded that was
definitely it all right so all right it
goes to
S3 what you mean it goes to
S3 wait wait uh I need to check my my oh
[__] yeah sorry it was my my mistake you
have proxy on so yeah everything went
through burp man dude that's hilarious
okay so so we we've been dealing with
some issues with fron cutting in and out
for this past like 20 minutes and you
know what it was he left freaking Burt
proxy on so classic hacker mistake here
um so I'm not sure really sure where
where it cut out but we'll we'll bring
it back around in peace burp State yeah
see yeah your burp file just blew up um
but yeah okay so you know you talked a
little bit about about you know the
testing methodology where you're you're
thinking about you know the code
structures you're thinking about things
like variable typing for and I will say
you know uh when you said typing for the
first time I was like yeah man you know
everybody types when they're hacking I
was like what the heck are you talking
about typing is one of our greatest
talking about typing as well oh my gosh
that's really funny but um so I guess I
wanted to dive a little bit into that so
we've seen the side already we've or at
least we've talked a little bit about
the side of like uh exploitation fronds
you know once you see a weird issue you
you poke at it you model out the code
you know you're thinking about how the
developer would have implemented it and
you're thinking about how you can
validate those assumptions by triggering
different edge cases throughout
throughout the code base
um I'm curious about flushing a little
bit more out about your your hack hacker
methodology because one of the things
we've seen in in the past with hackers
that have come on here is that you you
have a couple extremes right you have
people that are you know um that go
really hard on the Recon stuff and
you've got people that that go really
hard on the um you know on the on the
manual hack
right um and so uh there's definitely
different types of hackers but I've seen
you do do both and I think when you've
got someone that can do both it it
creates a crazy result so but I did want
to ask you you know if you identify a
little bit more as as one or the other
do do you identify a little bit more as
a manual hacker or as a a wide hacker
you know focusing on recon to find weird
stuff or do you see yourself as a mix of
the two so I I began mostly so I think
it's it's a matter of difference in
terms of like where I'm at like so I
would say I started off of course manual
because everybody does that you need to
figure out what to do before you can
automate sure I then went into like full
fullon automation like I wanted but but
there was always like I always had the
argument on like you can't automate if
you don't know what you're looking for
and if your whole idea is to find
something you don't know of H you can't
really automate it all so I was never I
was never a fullon
automation if that's a word yeah I I was
more on like I automated a bunch of
things I knew what I was looking for but
then I always kept this thing where I'm
like I'm Gonna Save it all and and I'm
going to look through it and I'm going
to see The Oddities myself sure because
I don't know what what I will find there
things will happen much faster than my
knowledge
about what it what it is basically um
but then then it came I think it
happened I took a break from bug hunting
or like break it was probably like one
and a half year or something like
probably during covid mostly yeah where
where I I didn't want to do any live
hacking events I wasn't really looking
for bugs in in any way during almost two
years I think um and when I came back I
kind of realized that similar to I think
what other bug Hunters that like want to
start off realize is that there's so
many people that are doing automation
that is like ridiculous like seriously
like they they do things so fast I I
tend to I spoke a lot about my
automation back in the day and I told
them like yeah I'm doing like every
eight hours I'm looking and they're like
every eight hours I'm doing it every 20
minutes everys you know like exactly and
I'm like they're like you're missing out
on so many things I'm like I can imagine
yeah and I'm like do I want to invest
the time to like speed up my my
automation just for those bugs and I it
came to the conclusion that like no I
don't I I rather I rather spend you know
manual time trying to figure out really
cool bugs than trying to like like reach
to the point where I'm like at level
with other automation ISS yeah
automation is I love that word it's a I
think we're going to Art arts and aut
you know yeah and it's actually funny
you know I actually had that exact same
path you know except I sort of skipped
the part where I was doing manual
hacking in the beginning like when
because there were so many Resources by
the time I started you know when I
started I guess in 2017 2018 you know
you had already put out talks you know
people were putting out talks on how to
do stuff so I had a pretty decent flow
of like bug Bounty writeups and stuff
like that to read and then I leveraged
into automation but then I came to the
same conclusion you did which is is like
well maybe a little bit different of one
but essentially in in order to compete
at this at this game at the top level
you have to be constantly refactoring
your code yeah and it's a grind right
and it and it's going to make it more of
a pro you're going to be become more of
a programmer than you are of a hacker
because um you know you're constantly
having to refactor code um and and so I
I also sort of leveraged a little bit
more or switched over into into manual
hacking a little bit more and it's been
fun to see see the results of that as
well um I I I think like and when I also
when I think about it like when I
mentally think about like what do I
wanna like end up with or like what do I
want to succeed with it's not that I
like oh I I dream of finding a unclaimed
S3 bucket like that's that's really not
the the bug that I'm I'm like I will go
home exactly and be happy about the the
bug I will go home be happy about is the
one where I'm like I did this thing over
there and that gave me a little piece of
the puzzle and then I went over there
and did that and now I I can access the
server like with an RC like those are
the kind of bugs that I'm like oh I'm
gonna feel so proud and it it's like
it's gonna it's gonna hold up for you
know more than a week probably sometimes
a year that bug has the value of like
and I I will not find that by writing
Automation and finding an unan bucket or
you know environment variable file
laying somewhere that might be helpful
into doing other things but you know
it's the the fun the fun things happen
when when I go deep so I I absolutely
shifted over to like go deep deep fullon
you know go you know so deep that that
people are like but move on man like
stop looking at that thing uh but but
I'm like keep digging and like some
sometimes there's something falling out
from it and like you realize you know
and I have I have all these examples of
you know running on a private program
but but still you know grinding it for
for months and and even collaborating uh
with with Matias in this case and like
we couldn't figure figure one thing out
and it was like how does this work and
why is it happening and like he was he
was at a concert I think it was I don't
know if it was like Iron Maiden or
something but he was at a concert and I
was writing him messages because we
often chat without the other one
responding like that's that's how we
communicate like a synchron is very very
much a synchronous and I was writing to
him like okay but this worked like I
don't know and and like it took probably
two or three hours and that chat message
history is like is a beauty of itself
because it's like this happened I think
it this oh oh my God like it ended up in
like being like total disaster and and
it was like you know ring the bell and
it like one of the most beautiful bugs
I've ever seen and it was just just that
grind of like we've been having this for
for months knowing that there's
something there but we couldn't figure
it out and we came to that conclusion
it's like it's so beautiful and it's and
it's like that's the kind of bugs I want
to com like like continue to you know
bring home or you know talk about in in
the future yeah absolutely I I I feel
like for a long time there was this
like there was a lot of manual hacking
that went on and then there was like a
few years kind of like right before Co
like around Co and then like during Co
where like a lot of people realize that
there's so much scope and there's so
much stuff out there that you can make a
lot of money just by doing Automation
and like automation isn't a particularly
difficult thing there's a lot of tools
out there stuff like nuclei and all
these like Frameworks and things that
exist that let you kind of just like
duct tape and bootstrap stuff together
and just like build these little
pipelines that do like a lot of like
really efficient work
and so a lot of people just really like
Dove head first into that and just
started like scanning for Stuff finding
subdomain takeovers finding bucket
takeovers finding like you know cves
that you could just like automate into
you know easily reproducible reports and
bugs and like that's a it's almost like
a separate bug Bounty space AB because
it's like you're basically at this point
you're not really like fighting over
like complexity of bugs or like how this
app like interacts with other parts of
the app or how this service or this
website might like you know be leveraged
by another part of the application or
another part of the company it's more
just like how fast is your tooling and
like how good can can you beat the other
person is your internet better is you
know are are is your scanning faster you
looking at the right things yes and I
really love this manual hacking type of
mentality like me and Justin have
discussed this a little bit because as a
full-time Hunter I think it's a lot
easier to either fall more towards
automation or at least towards like less
complex findings because you need that
cash flow you need to be having reports
going in all the time but I also like I
love not feeling obligated to have
reports in because that gives you that
opportunity to do what you're talking
about like go deep with the application
get intimate as we like to
say learn the ins and outs of this
application become like almost a
developer essentially at the company
where you understand more about how
stuff is going on in the back end than
even somebody who works at the company
does because that really gives you all
those insights into where stuff is like
faltering or where there might be weird
mechanisms or these systemic patterns
like you talked about where you know you
realize oh this is like a common mistake
or Pitfall that they made maybe they
made this here and here and here and and
so on and I just love that that
mentality of just like you know ignore
the the sort of the The Flash and the
the Glamour and stuff just like bug
after bug after bug and find that really
really cool deep [__] and I I agree I
think I think one of the so I went full
bug hunting mode last I would say
beginning of September October kind of
and and the decision I made was
happening during that summer and I
because I had those kind of you know
anxious uh things also like will I be
able to like pay my own salary or like
how how how can I figure out the
economics around doing this fulltime uh
and at that point I I I had I had luck
because I I done like I did a
zoom on uh like bugs on zoom and they
paid me out that summer and they paid
really well for those bugs so at that
point I'm like okay this is my buffer so
I have a buffer now of like if I would
take like my normal salary I would I
would like last these amount of months
okay so these months I can I can figure
out if I should you know go automation
or continue doing because those bug I
found was like no automation it was just
like trying to figure out how everything
worked uh and used that time to like
figure out first like where should I
hunt like what program takes care of me
what program you know treats my bug bugs
in a way that I feel appreciated or like
they value my my time and then also like
economical wise like where should I
spend my time to like align the return
on investment in a way that makes me not
stressed you know going forward um and
when I figure those things out like
where to look I still trying to figure
out like what programs I should focus on
but when I figured out some of it at
least that helped me a lot in into like
deciding that going deep was actually
you know H monetary wise a good decision
for me to like don't be afraid that that
I won't be able to pay myself a salary
basic yeah yeah I think you definitely
see if you look at the numbers I think
you'll see a higher um return on
investment of time right in a highly a
higher hourly rate if you do deep bugs
but the thing with with automation is
you get to have this and and I
experienced this when I was in
automation game if you take time off you
still get bugs right which is just huge
for like relief right you know like I
don't know what it is for me but like
even if I have a ton of money sitting in
the bank if I see that trending downward
while I'm taking a break or if I if I
know like hey I'm not finding bugs right
now
that just bothers me you know and
imagine it's kind of like a it's it's
definitely a psychological problem um
you know for sure but because I think
you should be able to rest in both
States whether you just popped you know
100K in bugs and now you take you know a
couple weeks off and you've got that
100K sitting in the bank and you're like
all right I'm fine or whether you've got
you know 20K in the bank and you're you
see it going up and up and up and up
with the bugs you know those are the
same the same things but you know
psychologically it's it's it's very
different I think we also have a whole
episode about like picking the right
program and I think you you covered this
a little bit but it's really important
especially like when you're doing
full-time hacking to have the right
program you mentioned like once you find
like a program who really respects you
as a researcher and your reports and
like handles the things that you're
submitting and takes it very seriously
and is you know responsive and all these
types of things like it makes a really
big difference
to like I I I I almost want to say that
it increases the quality of the bugs
that you find later
because like you have this relationship
with the company where you want to show
them like hey I found this really cool
thing on on your app like let me show
you like let me take it one step further
like let me you know I I bet you thought
that last bug was cool but how about
this
one you it's almost like a challenge and
um if you find a company that that not
only treats you right but pays correctly
like if you have a a program say they
pay like 5K crits and they mediums are
like
750 a couple medium like you know you're
at like five mediums almost there right
and so it's like if you have automation
that's finding a bunch of mediums versus
it takes you a week or two to find like
a really bad crit but it's only going to
get paid 5K then that trade-off isn't
always worth it but if you have a
program that's paying like 30k crits and
maybe their mediums are like one or 2K
well that makes a big difference and
then your time is really really worth
like spending that time finding that
critical and not spending it doing
automation or like trying to find a
subate take yeah let let let me jump in
here and say you know I I think we've
made it clear enough but I want to
clarify we have tremendous respect for
people on both sides of the game um you
know and you know uh the there's
definitely so many challenges of of
Recon and so many challenges of deep
diving stuff um so hopefully this has
given a little bit of insight into the
the thought because I think All of Us
Joel more so than me but you know have
leveraged a little bit more into the
whole finding very high impact bugs um
you know with the majority of your time
and and fron as well um and so okay but
we've already been talking for a while
and I two bullet points down on my
little list so let me let me let me let
me just started the episode he's like we
got so much to cover like 30 minutes
we've talked about two topics yeah like
super stressed over here because Bam Bam
Bam next next let me get back to my list
okay um no okay so I I do want to ask a
couple things we'll keep these pretty
pretty rapid fire I think um so you know
you said you you identify more now as as
sort of a deep deep dive hacker which I
think is is on point um and so and and I
think I know the answer to this cuz you
already alluded to it but I'm wondering
how much time it takes you to how much
time you normally spend on a program on
average and how much time it normally
takes you to find some bugs that you're
proud of I would say so I haven't jumped
between programs that much since I
started with this methodology but the
one the times I've done it during these
two years I would say
I I think and this is like where where
the Imposter syndrome also hits hard uh
every time it's because whenever you
change your switch program you basically
have these you know sometimes for me it
can take up to like three days until I
actually find you know something that I
I think is relevant or or valuable yeah
and so so and I I've trained myself to
not like I you know you feel [__] during
that time like you hate yourself
you think you're a fraud and all these
kind of you knows come up but at some
point you're like okay but no I I I know
this time is there you need to invest
the time and you know because and and
it's interesting also because if you
compare the first day you see a bunch of
you know variable names or like
parameter names and like what the what
is this what is this I I have no idea I
just want to find a bug like ignore what
they are like and the third day you're
like oh I know exactly what that
parameter does
that's why you need to like those days
to like get that you know mindset of
like like the taxonomy for example
taxonomy is a huge huge thing like what
do they call you know this kind of
object and model like as soon as so I I
tend to like write down tonomy for
myself just to like understand what is
referencing what then at at some point
like that's also a really good receipt
for okay they're call calling it a
little bit different here like they use
they used you know a pascal case over
here but there's snake case over there
and like those kind of things is like
indicators that there are multiple
people doing doing things here and
they've named it differently like that's
an indicator um and those things takes
probably like three days to realize that
this is an outlier for example so let me
let me just highlight that just for the
listeners okay do you guys hear the
level uh of depth that he's he's
describing here he's describing the the
case the case of parameters and and and
he's he's taking notes on the the
verbage the the wording the taxonomy of
the various parameters and and end
points and and this is the kind of stuff
that you would think is getting too
minute too too detailed but is totally
not no no because every single every
single thing every time you go that deep
you get a further and further a little
bit little just a little little tiny bit
closer to understanding what it's what
it's looking like for this whole
application and and that that little
step little step by step there makes all
the difference in the world when it
comes to sort of blackbox texting when
at the end of the day you're totally you
know you're totally looking at a black
box you know you have no idea what
you're working abolutely
so there's some there's some good tricks
there I'm with you man like I yeah yeah
I mean there's some good tricks you can
do like sometimes I just take the full
scope and I I search for the host in
burp search and then I copy everything
into an XML file and I have like a
unpack uh unpack burp state or unpack
burp uh list H and then I take the body
of the request and then I take all the
words I have and then I sort them and
make them unique and then I can see like
okay there's like intent id but there's
intent underscore ID and then suddenly I
can like go that way to like find all
these in in parameters as well yeah and
and those are those you know if You' got
intent id Snak case and intent uncore id
you know those are parameters that were
clearly implemented by different
developers right or or different you
know um life cycle flows right right
there right and so um you know there's
definitely a good chance that if every
single intent uppercase i ID is secure
that sometimes the intent underscore ID
will not be secure right so having that
that sort of Frameworks in place can
really help you um understand you know
that the app from a holistic perspective
and just take take you know also I just
want to shout out that that ability to
take notes to to or not necessarily take
notes but like to process the data that
you've got there you know exporting to
burp taking the time to write the XML
unpack script which is something I've
never done by the way because it's just
such a pain share it I can share it it's
awesome yeah that that would be great um
is something that will differentiate you
from other hackers right you don't even
have to know that it's the right thing
to do you know so many people are like
man should I spend my time doing this
doesn't matter it's going to make you
unique as a hacker let's say you do that
nothing comes of it you still saw more
of the application than someone else who
who hasn't done that right you you
looked at those parameters a little bit
differently you know because you
unpacked everything so it's the things
that make us unique hackers like that
that that really allow different people
to find different crazy bugs yeah I also
think that there's like a whole aspect
like the whole becoming almost like a
developer within that environment where
if you learn the terminology and you
learn what things mean so many
developers use abbreviations and stuff
to like represent things like they
they'll they might uh you know take
something that represents some system
right and they might abbreviate it as
characters and just start using that as
an acronym like throughout their
application throughout different like
you know end points or parameter calls
and stuff A lot of times I'll look at
something like that and I'll say like
what like what is what is this like what
is this these three letters what is this
supposed to mean like what what does
this represent to the developer and once
you identify at a lower level like what
does this actually mean what are they
referencing when they're saying you know
these three characters or whatever you
can really start to unpack hidden
functionality and this type of stuff
that may even exist that you know you'll
start to stretch to different ideas like
oh maybe if they're calling uh an
endpoint with a different three-letter
acronym maybe I can toss my three-letter
AC then I know what this means maybe I
can hit a different service or something
right and and I think like getting to
that level of just being like what does
that mean or what is this parameter
doing or what does this represent can
let you get that much deeper
understanding and be able to dive deeper
within the application so much easier
yeah yeah 100% um so let me let me ask
this then
um I I have
seen I'm thinking specifically at the
last Live Hack event we were both at
when we were sitting at this table and
we were like slamming our heads into a
wall um on this one specific bug for a
while um how how often do you find
yourself sitting in front of a request
and trying things sort of incessantly
versus sitting back staring at the
ceiling and thinking about the bug like
and and I and I know that this is kind
of a hard question CU it's very um you
know abstract but just give me your gut
your gut feelings on how much time you
spend actually handson iterating versus
uh just sort of thinking and ideating
yeah so so I have I have a bunch of
things I I tend to do when I I get to
the point where I I can't figure it out
yeah like it's all everything from you
know collecting my own kind of word list
from that uh asset just to like find you
know things in there that like can make
me understand what this is uh up to up
to the point where where as you said
like I I take a walk and I'm like
thinking about it and like how why does
it behave like it does or what is it
trying to you know what data is it
trying to fetch or or similar so
sometimes I I would say both work
sometimes you know complete brute
together with very context related
information yeah like for example
generic word lists for me is not really
helping that much I wouldn't say that
you know word list found on you know a
really large word word list works that
well I would the ones that work are are
when when you can like apply the context
to what you're actually looking at
that's when you're getting the nice nice
hits and and but but in in in in the
other aspect also is like sometimes you
just need to think about it and you know
Google error messages is like awesome
thing as well as soon as you see an
error message that is like this is not a
generic error message like then you can
start digging down like maybe it's this
and maybe this is the database I'm
injecting into or whatever or even maybe
an error message that kind of looks like
a generic error message but is
specifically you know or it has like you
know a format that is that is very very
different from also like if error
messages look the same on a Target and
suddenly one error message doesn't that
that is also like okay the all the other
ones had you know square brackets around
the error code but this one does not
like those could be also indicators that
okay there's another thing causing this
error message yeah no absolutely yeah
absolutely I think like one of the
really underutilized things is Googling
stuff with quotes around
it all the time just like if I see an
error you Google something with quotes
around it it does exact yeah yeah
exactly like that we did that at the
last event you know we're talking about
right now like what is this like what is
this system what is this using what is
this technology and just search the
error message and immediately there's
100 Google results all mentioning the
same exact thing you're like oh okay
it's that okay that's that's it so last
question about the hacker methodology
piece so it seems like you spend a good
amount of time on your targets it give
me just sort of like a gut feeling on
like how how much time you spend on the
average
Target I would say so I would say three
days is is an investment first you might
not get anything from it so I've done
this like short assessments kind of
thing where I'm like okay I'm G to focus
on this program and what what has
happened for me is like one and a half
week yeah is is it's a it's a time for
me where I know I'm going to find
something good I don't know how bad it
will be but I know I will find something
that will be good so one and a half week
has been a really good uh way for me but
also like you have kids so it's like
right you don't know where where you're
going to spend that one and a half week
are you going to spend it on the night
are you going to spend it you know in
the office times or are you going to
spend it like at all like there could be
you know and and often like when you
submit you know a bunch of bugs at the
same time or like in the in the matter
of of days uh you always have this trios
you know massage yeah that is like it it
can be
especially like my my reports are like
sometimes two to 4,000 words uh my my
reports are insane man like they are
they are my blog posts are sometimes are
small compared to my blog post oh my
gosh I'm writing them manually it's not
like copy pasting a boil plate of like
how it's actually like step by step
showing you know sometimes I I'm showing
even how I came to the conclusion that
there there's a bug and I have like very
long impact explanation and you know
everything is like typed from from from
the frontal cortext yeah 100% yeah but
so but then you have so that half week
afterwards is like Tre triage massage
basically yeah there's always that like
getting through yeah you get it through
they find out it's not a dupe and then
it's another week of yes this is how you
reproduce
it that's a good that's a good side
effect also of going like deep into a
program like compare like live hacking
events are are an exception to the to
the rule but but I haven't duped once in
in all all like this full time since
August last year uh except for live
hacking You' duped me you
stupid like I was like We'll that too so
so like let's say for example that
program right that was a that was a
challenge um and and so how long would
you spend on something like that that
one I spent I to be honest that one was
new for me so I didn't know what to
expect so I submitted that bug only uh
and it was two hours or something yeah I
mean I didn't spend [__] on on that but
the funny thing was that it was I think
it was very valuable for me not to spend
more time because I had a hunch that
they might not be as you know receptive
to that vulnerability receptive to the
report as I thought so in in that sense
I think I did a good investment not to
spend more time yeah and that's also a
thing where you like especially when it
comes to new programs I'm like very very
restrictive on like like the worst thing
you can do is like you spend much time
you find a really bad bug and then you
continue and you submit bugs and you
have no response yet and you're like
investing so much time and then suddenly
they respond and they don't treat you in
a good way yeah and you're like why did
I continue yeah you you you spoke really
I've heard that before from from other
people in the in the in the podcast also
it's like do don't invest too much in
the beginning like you won't you won't
gain anything from submitting you know
50 bugs in the begin you're you're only
gambling with your own time like don't
do that absolutely yeah you can gamble
with that time when you know the
receiver and you know what what to
expect from them you have to validate
validate the program and validate your
threat model because on on one hand you
know you be it could be the program just
being [__] right that's one possibility
you know they could just be a bad
program or you have misaligned your ex
exactly think is a is a threat or not or
you could have misaligned your threat
model and and and that's not anybody's
fault except maybe you know one could
argue that the team should have uh you
know provided more insight into their
threat model sure in their policy which
I would love to see more of in general
but you know like you said it's a gamble
if you're not if you're not you know
validating that threat model in advance
because um you know it's very easy for
issues to to to come out of that um and
so okay all right first section of my of
my of my notes are are done here yes um
so here's what here's what I'm thinking
we're going to go from here
okay I have uh compiled together let's
see one two three four five
six uh articles some of the best hacking
articles I've ever read written by
France over the years starting in 2017
spanning all the way up to I think 2022
or 2023 the latest one um and I just
want to kind of walk through these and
talk about mentality I want to talk
about the technical details of them so I
hope you reviewed them because I don't
know about you but I if I if I wrote
something you know 6 months ago and then
somebody asked me about it you know 6
months later then I'm screwed uh cuz
but we'll see um okay so the first one
and we'll link all these in the
description as well I would it's not
even something that I would recommend it
is mandatory reading for any listener of
critical thinking to go and read all of
these um so please keep that in mind um
the first one that I wanted to talk
about was this whole uh AWS S3 thing so
yeah um if any you know for the
listeners here um S3 bucket takeovers
and S3 bucket issues now are one it's
one of the most hottest it's one of the
hottest topics in in Cloud security um
and all of this originates with this man
right here fron um who who sort of
coined the S3 yeah the S3 bucket
takeover um and so I I want to kind of
you know flash back to 2017 here um
you're seeing this new technology sort
of coming on the scene and you're seeing
it implemented in lots of different
places on all these different programs
how do you come um how do you identify
this
issue it was actually earlier earlier it
was actually 2014 the first the first
blog post about it was in 2014 October I
think yeah um and and back then back
then it was basically you know every
time you saw a 404 you like just like
moved on yeah exactly because it's like
wasn't nothing is there right uh so I I
think we we came to the conclusion like
I think it was
both S3 and there was some something
else that was also like I think heru was
and G GitHub GitHub Pages was one of
those so I think we just came to the
realization because we were looking at
like detectify was was getting built at
the same time and a lot of things we
were doing was around you know Finding
subdomains and and trying to identify
what what they were running and at some
point I think we we figured out that
like okay so uh
we started signing up on these these uh
you know I think was Shopify as well
like this these Sauce Services and
suddenly realized that you could just
like there were no verification at all
like we were on under the like
assumption in the beginning that you
need to validate your your that you own
the domain because that's how you do you
know everything else when it comes to
like Gmail or you know when you want to
run Gmail for example and and and and
realize that okay nobody's actually
doing this because it's like a
convenience thing to to like not use
that validation part uh and we started
reaching out to all these companies and
writing like okay somebody can just
hijack all these these uh companies uh
because they're pointing to you and some
of these some of the providers were just
like yeah but they're not our customer
anymore so why reading between the lines
that was what they were saying like it's
not our fault that you know they're not
paying us anymore or you know somebody's
going to have to pay us to hack them I
like thatone that's not our customer
yeah go for it no but so so I think and
and and a lot of them were like we
already know about this this is no no
big deal and and we were we were
screaming loud like please do something
about it like add the validation do you
know whatever like something you need to
do something and And when everybody
responded like not a single company
responded with like yeah you're right oh
my go we we realized like I we need to
get it get it out there and then it was
just a matter of like how many more are
there I I think the first blog post we
had we had like 14 maybe providers like
big providers that we decided to to
announce uh but at the same time there
were you know a huge amount popping up
since then of course still popping up to
this day and uh and S3 is one of those
that that like keeps on lingering uh I
know that there are there are some
changes happening or the like you can't
change S3 but you can you can do
implementations above it that is like
safe so there's something called S3
access points which is their addition to
it and access points always get like a
unique um hash in the in it so you can't
CL reclaim an access point so that's
that's like AWS solution to the problem
is to like make access point the the way
to actually access a bucket um but yeah
I think and like one of the big
challenges in the beginning also when it
comes to S3 was to figure out what the
bucket name was it wasn't always clear
even though you have it in the error
message it wasn't always clear uh what
the bucket and especially sometimes you
do want to know the bucket name even if
it's exists and I think that was the the
the whole idea with the bucket disclosed
was to figure out what the bucket was
named because if you knew what the
bucket was named you can make additional
API
on the side to that bucket to see access
level errors and stuff yeah that's
that's such an amazing little little
script there um and we'll we'll link it
down below yeah we'll link it down below
and it does still work to allow you to
identify what the name of a bucket is
and there's lots of really cool error
based stuff you can do with that too
where you're like creating um invalid
signed URLs that fail in such a specific
way that it like leaks the bucket name
so cool we have the same
me and Matias built the same one in the
beginning of this year for Google Cloud
Storage so we have a we have seven seven
decloaking methods for for uh for cloud
storage H and it's kind of helpful in
cloud storage as well because sometimes
you really want to know the name yeah
and it's very important for depending on
how your setup looks like so I think I
will talk with Matias to get it out as
well I think it's very fun to have
that's awesome cloaking I I love the the
that like terminology I think this
applies to more than just S3 buckets
where like this is it's very similar to
like origin server detection where you
know if you're trying to bypass a W for
example you find what the origin server
is or a way to talk to the origin server
directly and mimic is if your requests
are going through the ra wff then often
times you can just bypass the W directly
and it's very similar to like S3 where
you might have some subdomain that's
maybe it's talking to a backend service
instead of actually just being a c name
um to the bucket
and if you can figure out some to ER it
or you know get get it to basically
Oracle to what the bucket is then you
can you know maybe read some data that
you shouldn't have access to you can
list the bucket maybe you can do you
know whatever it really depends on the
context I love that that methodology the
decloaking is is applicable in so many
aspects like you mentioned as well like
with a reverse proxy or an origin
structure you know if you can leak that
backend URL there's there's a decent
chance that you might be able to use
that in a vhost you know somewhere else
at a load balancer level and hit that
back in server Direct and just bypass
all of the middleware authentication
that they've got in place so we've seen
that time and time again and it's a it's
an awesome technique and and that's
another one of the things that kind of
comes out of the security research is is
the the impact the the conceptual impact
is very wide reaching right it's
applicable to lots of different areas
which is which is really cool um okay so
there's lots of other stuff you can dive
into with this with this blog post that
will link the and actually I didn't even
have the one I'm looking back now cuz
you said the one in 2014 and then
there's also another one which I missed
in 2016 where you're talking about
cloudfront stuff and um oh yeah and that
was fun yeah that was good memories and
the the the uh the trailing dot dude
like oh yeah there was a bug there was a
bug like in a live hacking event right
just like two years ago or something
that that one of the bugs the best bugs
in that live hacking event was a
trailing do yeah so it still happens so
for those of you excuse me for those of
you that don't know about that actually
you know France why don't you tell them
a little bit about trailing Dot and what
that does conceptually yeah so I think
the the blog post mentions specifically
cloudfront so what happened with
cloudfront was that when you went to in
this case it was like paypal.com it
wasn't paypal.com I think it was car.com
so you went to car.com and you would be
served a page through cloudflare uh but
the whole idea with like how internet
works or like the dubd dub Works was
that H you can always add a TR Cloud
Player or Cloud front Cloud front Cloud
front okay yes Cloud front yeah yeah you
can always add like a trailing dot to a
domain yeah because that's the it's
called like fqdn like a fully qualified
domain name is actually ending with a
DOT uh they've just removed it for like
I think for like Simplicity or something
yeah H so a trailing dot should always
you know serve similar things or just
give an error or whatever and in
cloudfront it gave an error but it gave
the error that looked like nobody has
claimed that domain so I went into
cloudfront now you can't do this anymore
because cloudfront wants you to validate
that you own the domain but back then
you could just add it as a c name to
your cloudfront and it had like a client
side validation so you couldn't add a
trailing dot it would say you can't but
if you like captur the proxy if you take
the like it was like a G grpc request
and you modified that little thing in
the request with a DOT you would add
that to your to your own host and then
you could serve whatever you want on the
on the trailing Dot and funny thing was
that cloudfront has cookie logging so it
will log your cookies also and and
cookies are working both on the fq fqdn
and the regular domain so if you had
cookies sign into PayPal and or car.com
and then went to car.com dot you would I
would get your cookies um and I started
getting those logs and I saw like people
were clicking on emails and then I
realized why are they getting this from
clicking on emails because they write
please hello my dear friend go to
car.com Dot and then the dot would be
you know included in the link because I
mean it's a link right uh so that was
the reason why so many came to the dot
domain because it it was like in the end
of a sentence wow so this doesn't even
really require user interaction at that
point because people are just going to
that domain natively yeah yeah yeah yeah
absolutely so that was that was the
scary part uh and and it was a long
process from that part like PayPal
obviously fixed it by by reclaiming it
themselves yeah but then it was a long
discussion with AWS also getting them to
like you know you need to normalize this
and so they also treated this as a as a
bug themselves wow do you feel like a
lot of the bugs that you found have led
to those sweeping sort of ads changes
like uh yes yes yes I do like one of the
one of the things that I I talked a lot
on I had a o event talking about the DNS
and Route
53 uh and and suddenly they took a took
a couple of years but they fixed it and
that is one of the most impressive
patches I've ever seen like I have no I
like I dream of the day somebody tells
me how that mitigation was done like
seriously like it's impressive as hell
they do they they do something out of
the out of the box thinking there honest
they really do and I've tried me and
chubs and plenty of other hackers have
spent so much time trying to bypass that
mitigation because if you can there's a
treasure Trove of bugs uh there you know
being able to reclaim these these
domains um but yeah that dude that was a
sad day for me man whenever they fix
that that bug because that was my that
was my cash cow when I was in in you
know you see automation also have these
you know oh [__] now now the curve going
down right it happens in automation as
well especially it I think it punches
you harder when those things happen in
automation I I I forgot to say that but
but when automation gets with something
happen with your Automation and goes
like that that's a panic you don't want
to end up with like that Panic is worth
worse than having a vacation and you go
you see it go down absolutely 100%
especially when you've dumped so much
time into it technique like I spent
weeks you know months of actual time you
know like on hands on the keyboard time
refining my my Route 53 flow and and and
just to be clear Route 53 takeovers are
still possible in some capacity but um
it's it's very limited in compared toed
yeah yeah and so um definitely changed a
lot and and that was that was The Day
The Day the Music Died For Me That was
the that was the day that that I was
like you know what I think I'm done with
this [__] uh
and so yeah all right so man I missed so
many articles you know when I when I
just going back I just kind of
cherry-picked some of my my FR you know
favorite moments but now I'm St you know
why I post post things because the bugs
turn boring after a while right so this
is this is my outlet to like eliminate
me from looking at them anymore because
I hope that someone else will look for
them yeah that sounds pretty I to ask if
you take notes but it's it's yeah that's
true but it's my way of like moving
forward
like if I if I out like myself in a way
that like like my secret tricks if I
just get them out there I can move on in
finding new new things yeah it pushes me
forward like and that's amazing for the
community too what a benefit and and
friends can I ask I mean do you do you
like writing in particular like do would
you say that you enjoy writing yeah I
think I think it's a necessity almost
since I spend so much time on like
writing reports yeah however like it's
hard for me to like sit down and say now
I'm going to skip hacking and now I'm
going to write a a you know a blog post
about something
because as what often happens is like
I'm not writing a short little blog post
on what I did yesterday it's like it's
gonna be like a huge article and I need
like I have one here that that I'm I'm
still cooking on it's been cooking since
January and I know for a fact that I
like I can't start you know directly
going at it I need I need to explain a
lot of [__] before I can come to the to
the conclusion of what I found and it's
going to take it's going to take a week
two weeks maybe and it's going to be
painful like a lot a big part of writing
blog post for me is like painful painful
you know going back and realize how hard
everything was or how long it took and
like I really want to emphasize that
also in the latest blog post I have it's
like it's a big focus on how much pain
goes into like wa like spending that
time and it's great that you mention
that because I will and and I'm not sure
if you're talking because you mentioned
just a second ago you you you had a a
vlog post you're working on I think
yesterday so I'm very interested to pick
your brain on that but um I'm I'm
talking I'm talking about um the account
hijacking using Dirty Dancing one one of
my notes for that one and it's on the
list that we'll talk about later but
that that blog post is so beautiful
because it talks about the ups and downs
of doing security research right and it
talks about like whole concept of well
you know these gadgets you know needed
to leak these tokens and stuff like that
the stars have to align in so many ways
for these to be there and and when you
go out there and you're like man I feel
like this might be a systemic issue
you're challenging something and you're
and you're you're betting against the
odds there and you're really like
putting yourself out there by spending a
[__] ton of time to assess so many
different different things and I think
it was great that you represented it
that way in the in the article and I I
think not to not to destroy the
discussion later about it but one big
thing with that the the whole the whole
idea about like my whole theory was not
based on finding that bug yeah like I
had zero bugs such for such a long time
during I didn't even have one you know I
I I had zero bugs I just had a theory
that oh this would be so beautiful if if
you could get this working like I had a
discussion in the office here I came
here and like yeah I'm I'm having a like
a Theory I'm working on but I don't know
if it's going to work like this is my
idea and if this works then maybe like
crazy right and then and I'm like I had
nothing so so that was it was such a
gamble it was it was 100% a gamble on
like let's then go look for it like how
like I had no idea how to do it so that
was very painful also in the in the way
of like oh I'm really trying to as you
said like getting the Stars to align but
then suddenly like one of the my my
favorite programs turned out to have
that thing that that was the like the
trigger that okay there I I'm right like
there is something here can I come up
with other you know idea gadgets or
whatever so everything came out of ideas
not from H like real life that was the
big difference with that blog post all
other blog posts are based on reality
first and then I'm moving backwards
trying to like see a systemic issue
about it this this was 100% idea trying
to squeeze it in it like very fitted
into 10 years since the blog post I
learned from like everything was aligned
like can I can I write a good OAS blog
post 10 years after my Idols wrote one
that would be that would be so it it was
very much like I really need to find a
way for this to work so yeah so when
you're like approaching stuff like we
we've talked a little bit about this
sort of like the really out of the box
type of thinking versus the like more
like data driven context driven
developer driven type of methodology do
you do you like going down that route of
more just like maybe this is happening
or do you find that it doesn't really
pay off most of the time so it it
doesn't pay off a lot of the times uh so
I I mentioned the Google Cloud Storage
the cloak like that was the whole idea
with that research was to find systemic
issues around that like we found some of
them but they weren't you know I
wouldn't say you couldn't execute them
in bug Bounty programs uh you could
maybe execute them you know if you want
to report things to Google but but for
go in Google's aspect they wouldn't be
like really bad bugs they would be like
coincidental
misconfigured together with like odd you
know conf like odd configurations for
Google but also for the customer using
them and stuff but so that turned out to
be like we don't really have anything we
have a a declo tool maybe that could be
fun to blog about maybe we can do like a
decloak blog post talking about the the
ways we found these decloaking
mechanisms and and maybe that could be
interesting like now I'm like now I'm
forcing myself to write these blog posts
because it would be weird talking about
the blog post that I so do you I mean
you mentioned before one motivation for
writing the blog post is you know it
gets it out of your head and allows you
to move on to something different so I
think that's a really great takeaway um
I wanted to ask about cuz you're
releasing all of these on detectify um
you know on the detectify blog um and
and so is that an intentional decision
is that to help you know detectify build
brand recognition because let me just
provide some context from from my
perspective as a hacker like you know I
I don't use detectify I'm not I'm not an
organization you know where where I
could use detectify but my respect for
detectify is like you know very high
because of all this super high quality
research same sort of thing you see with
Asino right where they're constantly
putting out high quality research um so
you know besides the motivation of of um
you know getting it out of your head
what are some other motivations that you
have for doing the blog post and hosting
them on detectify I think I think one
important aspect is like they I've been
a part of it for so long so it's
important for me to
like H I resp like I respect the whole
team so much that I want to show them
that that it's like very important part
of who I am and where I'm at as well as
like sometimes I actually like me and
Frederick sometimes collaborate on blog
posts and he's he's you know uh working
here uh from day to day as well so I
think it's like this office for me is a
very good way of uh doing you know uh
what's it called like brainstorming and
things like trying to Fig out things so
of most often I I tend to present to
them first what I'm thinking about sure
and then because of the knowledge here I
can get like feedback on like maybe you
should do this maybe you should do that
or maybe you should call it dirty
dancing which was like like Emily in the
office like you should call it it's like
sounds like dirty dancing to me like
yeah that's good name so I I think that
it's very helpful having a context
nearby where where a lot people know
exactly what you're talking about and
and you know the the technology so I
think that's that's very helpful also
like I'm I'm obviously still a part of
the techy right not not that I'm writing
any code and I shouldn't but but but
it's it's and I think also like I I
don't have a big gain I think on like
making my own personal blog and creating
a name out of that I'm more than happy
to like attach myself to a company that
I that I value and and like am a part of
much more than than doing it you know
privately trying to build a brand and
and you kind of get a a two for one when
you do it because I mean I don't know
maybe maybe it's just the fact that your
brand is already established you know in
the in the community right um but uh you
know when we when we look at this blog
post and we say Okay detective is
releasing this but fron is writing it
you know you kind of get um you know
it's almost like to to put it in SE
terms it's almost like you get domain
Authority on on detectify and you get
you know Community Authority from so
it's a good it's a good it's a good
thing and man when I'm thinking about
where to go next here there's so many
you know we could go down the route of
like let's talk about about Dirty
Dancing we could talk about uh you know
H hacking plus entrepreneurship and I
think that that is where I want to go
with this next one which is like
so you you go you come into this company
you know you started detectify with you
know know years ago with with you know
Matias and and them all based off of you
know uh that security research what what
role do you play in this company and
like what CU to me it kind of seems like
you just kind of run around and you're
like hey guys what if we did this blog
post and like what if like have you seen
this cool technical idea and like who
the heck are you to this company like so
it's a good that you say that because
like one of the things happening with
the companies that I I've built when
they are growing up
there is like a big discussion on like
how do we squeeze France into the
regular you know day-to-day basis like
what can we do so I was I was a a scrum
what was that called I was uh like a
scum scrum Breer no scrum breaker scrum
breaker okay so I went in and like we
should do this and like the whole scrum
team is like we hate you so I was I was
the scrum breaker and and and so and
every time when when it gets like more
than 40 50 people it's like how do we
fit this weird person individual into
this organization and it's like yeah how
did you how did you so one of the things
that I find really difficult and even
just the small entrepreneurial Endeavors
that I've been a part of is delegating
like and so when You' started these
companies have you had other players
that are you know the executive players
from the very beginning or how do you
how was it hard for you to up control or
delegate um you know uh jobs to
different people and how did you move
out of that okay so I I could say like
this one of the benefits I had was to
have a business partner early on that
was very much into sales and also into
managing that's awesome uh I think that
was the helpful part so I always had to
you know take the technical jacket on
and and and be the one in both in charge
of the team doing the technical things
but also uh together with the team
trying to figure out how to solve
certain things like in the beginning it
was me building you know building uh
everything and then we we got like our
first employee that was a developer and
we we we worked really well together so
we could start building it also like
this was an e-commerce platform it's
still alive it's called Sentra it was
smaller then it's bigger now uh but but
so when we started building Sentra uh we
uh I was always down on the floor so to
say
I was always a part of the team that was
like my whole concept of like my my way
of managing in the technical team was to
be just one one of the guys like I was
never you know doing any salary talks
that was never my my um my job I was not
doing any one in ones so one-on once was
do done by someone else I was the you
know CTO in the way that like I'm going
to play with new technologies I'm going
to try to execute them if I find
something
I'm I'm gonna I'm going to together with
the team like sometimes make a smaller
team out of the bigger team just to make
something reality as fast as possible
but that thing only works when you go up
to like when we we turn into 50 or 60
people that's when it's like really hard
to like take some people out of the dev
team and get to do some fun new thing
and then trying to move them put them
back again and like everybody's happy
like that that's not how it works so it
it became really hard for me to like
sque like be squeezed in and like get to
play with the fun toys H so I I've come
to the realization that like I can I can
build I'm I'm really good at like
starting from zero yeah and then when
when we we get up to 40 50 people I'm
like yeah just roll it out of the
picture yeah exactly that's that's
basically yeah and I think it's good for
everyone if I do that because else it's
just so much politics around I love how
he say that else else
thisse literally the program exceptional
is making into the verbage that's that's
amazing um yeah yeah so I think that's
that's the the aspect of it is is yeah I
don't know if that was an answer to the
question it is man it's it's a great I
mean what a great position to be in what
a dream of a position and I think so
many people that have the
entrepreneurial itch that are also
technical people dream of positions like
that of like okay I'm I'm seite you know
I I have influence on this organization
but all the crappy stuff like sales and
management I'm going to just not do that
and I'm going to do I'm going to we all
know that this is how it works best too
when you're operating in your area of
expertise when you're operating in your
passion so that just highlights the the
importance of trying to find someone who
who you know that's a partner that's
very passionate about sales and and
management and that sort of thing so
that you each can operate in your own
sort of you know expertise genre yeah
exactly yeah exper I also love that like
co-founder model where like it's really
hard to be good at everything and I
think it's much more of an anomaly to be
good at like both aspects of the
business like both the technical and
like the the the really refined like
fine point like how does the product or
feature service or whatever actually
work versus like getting it sold and
like customers and getting it marketed
and that kind of stuff and trying to
balance both of those things as one
person is really really difficult um and
oftentimes you either have to subsidize
that temporarily by like either taking
debt or using your own personal money to
like pay people to do that or you get
just like drowned in doing everything by
yourself and every single day is like a
12 to 16 hour day just like doing sales
and also writing the product and also
sending emails and yeah doing like
everything
so you can start out by having that
balance it's just like really it's not
that I it's not that we realized that to
begin with like I had salary talks but
the only thing happening was that I
raised everybody's salary like way too
much so it's like we we came like we we
had a gift no more salary talks for FR
no and I had we had like a Christmas
gift thing and we're like giving away
iPhones and it's like oh God have so
little money on on the first day of the
year afterwards and it was like maybe I
should shouldn't do this uh I should not
be the one in charge of like because I
wanted everybody happy like that was my
because yeah so I I came into this
podcast thinking fron is like some
hacker entrepreneurial genius and now
I'm leaving thinking fron is running
around annoying people until he doesn't
have to do the parts of the job that he
doesn't want him to probably that's
that's the truth I guess but it's like
yeah I mean there's some truth also to
like uh we we kind of realized like
where where do where is my execution the
best like the best place to be in and
like that that was the that was the way
to like grow very fast I I make a joke
about that but but really you know it it
that's the wisest thing to do truly and
and and so um yeah there's there's I
guess one of this is more of a personal
question for from from my perspective
one of the things I've struggled with is
is you know releasing that and and being
like all right you know I actually just
need to delegate this job to someone
else yeah and and the reason why I
struggle with that is because it's like
okay well a lot of times in the
beginning that means giving up Equity
right and and because you don't have the
money or if you do have the money you
don't want to you know I don't know just
syn all of your life savings into a
thing which actually you hear about
entrepreneurs doing all the time which
is just you know awesome and inspiring
um I mean is that is that what you what
you had to do I mean is that what is
that what you need to do is you just
need to give give the equity so that you
don't have to do this part of the job
and that's the right decision from your
perspective I I wouldn't say we had to
do that from the
GetGo at all uh to begin with but we
came I think uh our our perspective of
it has changed because of experience
like in the beginning we could actually
you know with a salary get people
engaged and get people to actually do
things and build and have fun like we
had a lot of fun building these
companies because it was so much
Hands-On we were like out there we were
you know I was developing things next to
the customers you know at like there was
a big like spectacle around you know how
we how we did business in the beginning
uh but but then I think um oh I lost the
thread uh yeah what was the question
well the question is is like I guess at
the end of the day what I need you to
tell me is that worth to to give to to
delegate these jobs right what happened
what happened then was that I uh when it
comes to
uh oh I had it yeah it came and then I
lost it and it's funny I I I get those
same sort of things when when I'm in
these situations on a podcast in
particular because it's so hard to keep
the it to explain there but it's like I
lost it I I think I think it's so yeah
so what happened was that we got people
employed without like giving away actual
Equity because we both had a really fun
place to be at because of the spectacle
but but also because they like we were
paying a fair kind of salary yeah but
then we like during all these years and
I think also it's like a um like how the
society works like there's a much more
talk now about you know getting Equity
when you're building a startup and stuff
and we we never we never really called
oursel a startup because we we made
money from day one so we we never you
know had a problem with the you know uh
MoneyWise uh but but I think that's an
important uh you know that that's an
important factor there because if you're
making money from day one if you build
your MVP and you actually have that
validated by by receiving money then all
of these issues of like start start to
disappear because at the end of the day
you can just hire someone and pay them
you know exactly because you you you do
have the money but then I mean a lot of
a lot of the money I made in bug
bounties have been invested into these
companies so we all we had that all we
didn't have that from the beginning
because that that wasn't how how worked
in the beginning but but during during
all these years we had that as a kind of
a way to solve a bunch of problems with
money obviously but but but then we also
realized that a lot of people that that
stayed for a really long time it was
much more valuable for them and of for
us to give them equity and a part of the
company yeah so that that that happened
after a longer while but now it's like
almost you know a standard thing like if
you join a startup you're getting a a
part of the equity in some form of you
know um like a pool similar uh Equity
pool and uh but but back then it wasn't
and I think that was helpful also into
like you know coming getting into that
but but I would say like what what
happened now later on with you know
getting a a CEO for example like we we
didn't want to be the CEO of this
company so we we you know found or CEO
found us in those cases it's always you
know you need to give up Equity
obviously um because you you want them
to be like you know they have to be
fully on you know active on on getting
the company to to where everybody else
wants wants it but uh so I I would say
it depends on what kind of position you
want to fill or what kind of things like
you don't need to give way equity for
for every every single you know person
that joins unless you like you can find
some
good yeah yeah that's true but I mean
you can find some some nice Equity
pooling kind of things where you get
like a you know a vesting time and stuff
so you know that people will stay at
least that time like but but it all
matters if you if you have like very key
positions like then then it that
discussion is relevant so so I I wanted
to ask one more thing and and I think
you know critical thinking as a podcast
focused specifically on bug Bounty hun
the entrepreneurial of this while isely
fascinating to me and think many of our
listen share interest um I think I may
move a lot more of my entrepreneurial
questions into a different segment that
maybe we'll release under the premium
Discord Channel or something like that
um but uh one last thing that I wanted
to ask about this was when you were
taking bug Bounty money and and putting
it into the companies how were you
thinking about that mentally were you
thinking about that as this is Fran's
money that he's investing into the
company
forting this income that is just direct
directly put right into theany yeah so
what what happened was we me and my
business partner we're 50-50 and uh this
was my way of uh providing so what I did
was providing quick capital and like
monetary wise the capital but he was
building like he he's he was in charge
of being the CEO and and everything in
the beginning so so he was in charge of
building the company you know making the
company more valuable but I was bringing
in the the quick Buck to actually make
it you know much more uh easy to solve
problems and to scale easier yeah yeah
to scale easier so so we we both agreed
that like we're putting in different
things but we need to align somewhere
here where like it's fine for me and
still fine for him and like I think it's
a weird balance also espe especially
when when the bug Bounty is like you can
go from one month you're getting you
know this amount and and a live hacking
event you get this amount and and it it
turned really complex in the end and it
turn turns into a lot of money if you're
if you're good at what you're doing so
uh I think it in the end it it was
probably like we we don't have that this
this uh setup anymore uh and I I think
that's that's probably for the best
because it can clearly like is align you
know interests time especially when when
it when it when it you know now you've
got a bug Bounty company where fron does
hacking and then we pay employees you
know like yeah yeah stream is fr's
bugs exactly it's like like like bug
hunting as a I don't know what to call
it it's like funding by bug bounty
hunting yeah for sure um okay so we'll
we'll I'm gonna I'm going to go ahead
and and cross off my uh hacking plus
entrepreneurial section here um thank
you for those awesome in insights frons
that's that's awesome and and I I know
you and I have had some personal chats
you know from time to time about
entrepreneurialship
entrepreneurship plus um that's a good
one was automation entreprene
entrepreneurial ship um no uh you know
plus hacking so uh definitely a lot of
wisdom to be received there um bringing
us back on track to the to the hacking
stuff I did want to talk about one of my
favorite um talks that you've ever done
which just essentially looked like
prophecy to me looking back in in the
past which is your attacking modern web
Technologies talk that you did in
2018 um uh almost exactly five years ago
yeah um and attacking modern web
Technologies there was so many awesome
pieces to this there was um app caches
and service workers uh you know there
was post message stuff there was upload
policies the the policies the S3
policies all sorts of stuff all over the
place so um once again mandatory
mandatory reading for anybody who's
listening um the crazy thing about to me
about this talk is like this is still
the stuff that we're talking about today
like and years ago right yes it's still
applicable yeah like I find bugs like
like sometimes I need to go back to
those slides because I find bugs for
those things exactly they have extremely
long lifespan those blog posts I'm
surprised myself that it's like still
working and this is something that's
really I think key listen and also help
helps for your for your brand as well
fron is that fron was was talking about
this stuff not not only doing this stuff
but talking about it publicly in 2018
five years ago and I I we talk about
post message still being an underserved
technology even to this day so keep an
eye on anything fron releases because it
it will very likely be applicable for
the future um uh so talk to me a little
bit about
uh app cach and and service worker stuff
and then um in conjunction with that the
beauty of the synergies between cookie
stuffing and and these Technologies yeah
so I think the the the the interesting
part with the app cach uh that that
happened there there were there were
many many fun things with it but H my
aspect of it was that I had a really old
Dropbox account and the old Dropbox
account were like grandfather
into a place where you could actually
host websites on on Dropbox user
content.com H and you and if you created
a new Dropbox account back then you
couldn't really run your own like you
couldn't render HTML pages and stuff but
if you had a legacy Dropbox account you
could but it was very limited into what
you could actually uh trigger with it or
like get it to to um render um and
I came to the conclusion that like what
can I do with an xss or running an xss
on on Dropbox user content and I I
remember I was talking with Matias then
and like what can we do like can we do
something and we came to the conclusion
like Okay cookie stuffing we can do so
you can make it like unable to actually
load because you're filling up the
cookie jar so much so when you're making
a request later on they will fail so so
question here so essentially what was
happening is you were able to host your
uh you know attacker controlled content
on a domain with with other attack you
know victim content on on that same
domain right yeah exactly what happened
was you got like a user directory on
Dropbox user content that you could host
data on uh and then you could uh I think
it was that I can see it now and I'll
I'll reference it it's slide 15 for any
of those of you that are following along
here um you know he's got dld Dropbox
userc content.com /u and then the user
ID and then wherever you would update
stuff and you got the xss not by
uploading an HTML file but by using SVG
right well I think it was an XML XML XML
you're right you're right yes XML yeah
so that was the thing everything else
was like you know getting downloaded and
position attachment uh but that was the
way but but if you had a new Dropbox
account you would never get the URL to
to you Dropbox user user content it was
only the Legacy Dropbox account had that
feature Ena um so that was the you know
the the weird part first with with
having that so we knew that we could do
cookie stuffing and what would happen
then if if somebody else sent a link
that would like four or four and or four
four five or something I or
five 411 I think maybe actually yeah so
that concept of of um cookie stuffing I
learned that from from you and from file
descriptor and and so I'm file
descriptor that that I learned it from
as well it was from I was going to ask
where did you get that knowledge and of
course it goes back to another Legend
file descriptor yeah file descriptor man
and and the funny thing with this bug
was that I think Matias was the one
mentioning we're coming back to F
scriptor so yeah he mentioned appcash
and I started reading up on what appcash
was doing and Matias as well and we
started like playing with that and
realized that we could you know host
reference a manifest into in the XML
file that manifest would then be loaded
and that manifest could be like a
regular text or whatever sure and that
text could contain and say that if if
you're unable to reach this website you
should have a fallback your fallback
page of this and that sure because the
whole app cach thing was based on you're
running an app and you're going offline
with your cell phone so you need to if
you reload the page you can still visit
it this is crazy and absolutely crazy
and what happened was that we realized
that in our user path we could put an
HTML file or an XML file and we could
say that this is the one that should be
loaded if you can't reach the website
and then we realized okay does the
cookie stuffing result in this thing and
it turns out that yes so we cookie
stuffed and made sure that if you
clicked on any other link we would just
steal the URL and then steal the the
page of that signed URL ourselves that's
amazing but the weird part of was that
when we did this blog post I don't know
exactly the date wise so our bug to
Dropbox was here and then here yeah and
then file descriptor comes out with a
talk uh explaining this bug and we were
like but we what we what so that that
was when we wanted we got the Dropbox uh
bug published so we could show that we
also figured this out that's crazy uh
and and so so he actually did a talk on
I think on oasp OAS talk or or something
else but
and so we came to the same kind of
conclusion uh which was great so I
wanted to like highlight that that like
sometimes people can like figure out the
same kind of things at the same time uh
and as you mentioned like there's like
the new thing I think I mentioning it as
well like service workers was a was a
like a a replacement for appcash but
back then I think it was like very hard
to like get a a service worker to work
because you needed to have like a
specific header on the service worker
file to allow it to run as a service
worker and there were a lot of like if
this and that that that had to work uh
to make it actually exploitable it it
seems like there's there's definitely
been some change in that area now and so
um you know I've definitely seen service
workers used in in lots of different
different contexts I believe you and I
always have to you know go back and look
at it but I'm not 100% sure but I I I'm
99 % sure that service workers can be
installed without a header now and the
header that if you do Supply an HTTP
response header what that will allow you
to do is reassign the uh the root path
the the the um Authority for that
service worker so if you you know even
though you're installing the service
worker at like sljs sjjs or whatever or
S W.J um then then you know you normally
just have Authority for the sljs
directory but if you're able to serve
that service worker allowed I think
header um then you can get uh and say
Hey give it permission to slash then you
can now affect all the resources ins
everywhere and it's it's such an
interesting technology especially when
you pair it with something like uh
subdomain takeover or or um you know
file upload because you can gain sort of
sort of a persistence in the browser as
well um using service workers and and um
you know that that ex we've seen this
also with truffle security released a a
tool called of cores I'm not sure if
you've seen it France but it's it's um
it uses a service worker in the
background to uh gain more time to be
able to attack different um websites
that have vulnerable hores
configurations even if you just visit
the page for just an instant you know so
there's so many um I think
applicable you know exploitation
scenarios for service workers um that
that we we got to keep our eye on
because they they have tremendous impact
yeah no and I agree but like I I guess
the core concept first is like you need
to have an xss to begin with and and
then you probably need to have arguments
on why that xss wasn't important in the
beginning and I guess like storage like
a bucket storage is a is a is a good
argument on like an xss there doesn't do
anything but if you have persistence you
can like show and I think that was what
the the the bug showed was like it's a
Sandbox domain it doesn't have any
impact but you have persistence and and
and that's the way to like gain access
to other URLs and stuff I just thought
about something France you know one of
the things we're going to talk about a
little bit later assuming we don't have
to cut for time is this middleware
misconfigurations that you you talked
about so what if we change that right
like we we changed the middleware
misconfiguration um and and so now we we
can use that to hit a different bucket
so just to be I'm going to give the tldr
of the of the middleware
misconfiguration thing if you if you
essentially with some enginex
configurations if you hit it if you put
a bunch of Escape characters you know um
new lines and stuff like that in the URL
and they have some specific proxy pass
rules um then you will be able to re
rewrite the rest of the request and hit
other S3 buckets or other backend
entities and host your own content Bas
exactly so what if we we chained that
with service workers right um where you
could then hit your own S3 bucket and
and issue but I'm wondering I mean you
still have stored stored EXs I guess
like somebody needs to visit your url
still and and that one would still make
you host whatever content you want on
that website so the but the the thing
you're gaining is the P the the
persistent thing that you can actually
make it load but they still need to
visit it once can you can you I'm
wondering though can
you set
response headers in
S3 yeah it depends if it's S3 website
you can some of them uh but I mean you
could also if it's S3 website you can
still redirect it to whenever like and
the depending on like the CSP for
example you can still redirect it
elsewhere I don't know if that helps you
though no no because what I'm thinking
is like when it' be cool if we could
insert some some new line characters
overwrite the the backend bucket right
have the bucket serve a a service worker
and then insert the service worker
header to slash so now so that we we we
gain you know that service worker
Authority um and get xss stored xss on
every single page that the user visits
within the browser I think that could be
really cool I mean S3 website would uh
allow you to do this if it's if the S3
website uh is if it's proxying you to S3
website and you can inject something to
modify what bucket it's going to serve
as a website you can inject whatever
head you guess it depends on the host
because I wonder I wonder if if we are
hitting so let's say they're sending a
request to you know whatever. s3. Amazon
aws.com and then we overwrite the host
header on that I wonder if it uses that
same load balancer or gen IP for you to
insert a header to hit S3 websites like
if you if you put in it doesn't okay no
h S3 website is also work because it
only responds on HTTP and not htps oh
what uh I have no idea why I think it
has something to do with like you're
supposed to put it behind something else
kind of cloud front or whatever but so
they they don't have the same load
balancer and you can't really get to S3
website from S3 as far as I know weird
yeah that's that's definitely it's very
isolated it's like a totally it's like
an overlay over S3 it's like S3 website
is like its own thing that there's
whatever you want basically yeah we'll
definitely have to research that a
little bit more in the the other area
that I was thinking that this could be
interesting is with crlf injection uh
into the response headers right if you
can do response
splitting assign the service worker
allowed header then you can make a
service worker out of the response
plating yeah sure that would be pretty L
you need something to load it I mean you
could probably make two crlf one crlf to
load a fake document and one CR R LF
that loads a fake service worker with
the header to install it absolutely that
should work yeah sure that's that's
that's some good that's some good [__]
right there um that's fun then you get
persistence yeah huh I'm just I'm
thinking about all the possibilities can
see the gears turning in as soon as he
hangs up he's he's got three programs
he's got to go look at then you then you
and then you can probably you know
escalate it to you know steal access
tokens stuff and yeah I mean um you can
probably do things with that I guess and
it makes it a lot
more it makes it I
mean it's a little bit interesting right
because technically what that could
result in then is we could get plain we
could leak the user's plain text
password without user interaction right
because like like you said what what are
we actually what we what do we actually
gain from this because at that point if
we have stored xss right then we can
just open up whatever we want in an
frame and then do whatever we want right
whatever yeah but but one of the things
that we can't do is is without more in
user interaction is leak the user plain
text password assuming they don't have
any crazy thing but but due to the
persistence you can uh you can get them
to yeah sure which which really
escalates pretty much
any and then I guess it's a reflected
more than stored but you turn it into
more of a stored client side
a client side stored xss Cent side
that's really interesting and then and
then this this is a really good um atto
mechanism because some especially if you
then proceed to cookie bomb like a a a
specific path that that issues you know
an off token or something like that it
forces the user to to clear their
cookies and reof the next time that they
they go into the application and at that
point if you've got the service worker
you can hijack the P the plane text
password yeah we this is this is some
good I think get you on this podcast
more often for this is great no no no
this is really good okay so um wow as
much as I would like to sit there and
just uh think on that for the next
little while let's let's try to keep
rolling um it's probably a sin but I'm
going to skip this whole uh section on
um S3 policies and Cloud policy uploads
which is a really awesome part of of the
attacking modern web Technologies uh
talk and I'm going to jump to something
that we've talked a little bit more
about on the podcast uh often which is
um the the post message stuff um
so
uh how did you because I once again
you're one of the one of the first
people that I I you know sort of
introduced me to post message stuff yeah
where where did you how did you come up
with this and then what what was it like
you know sort of seeing this did
somebody else's research spur this
thought in you or was it just how does
this work sort of that's that's a really
good question do you remember I guess is
the first question no I I don't I I
actually don't 100% remember where I
think I think like this I think there
were examples of vulnerable cases
already post like I wasn't the one
showing that you can exploit it uh but I
started to so I think I did a lot of
focus back then on I think it was
Dropbox sure maybe
yeah and I think it was so it was also
like payment providers there was
something because payment providers tend
to do a lot of and you had to talk
yourself about it yeah yeah and and what
happened was that there was a as a as a
huge amount of payment providers that
started moving over to post message and
you always had a really hard part
finding all the post message listeners
so as I did back then I was discussing
with Matias
like what how how do we figure these
things out and and we came to the
conclusion that like okay probably an
extension and then I sat down and wrote
a bunch of like you know inside ey
frames deep you know H post message that
that get listeners that get triggered by
actions and and a lot of different I
think it's still in the repository
there's like an example. HTML with a
bunch of listeners and and just to like
try to figure out what we can do about
it and I I I made my first uh version of
the of the extension and like okay this
will be useable like oh just the number
even though you have like five if frames
deep a listener the number counter on
the post message listener Chrome
extension will still you know increase
uh versus looking at the The Source
events Global events and you only see
the if frame you're currently selected
yeah I was like this is a terrible
functionality uh so I made my first
version of this and I I talked with the
Google team because I told them like why
can't you just like I don't want to
start building an extension like can't
you just fix so you can see all the
listeners in all ey frames yeah and
they're like no this is how it's
supposed to be and blah blah blah and
it's terrible and it's something
something that I talked about in my talk
as well but like yeah you got to do your
D in and you still even have to do your
due diligence to go and show where all
of the you know to to go sus all of the
listeners because something may not be
utilizing that listener right so in that
case it won't show up in post message
tracker so you still got to go through
and do it one of the and you know it's
my fault is as well because I haven't
contributed to that nice private repo
you put me on for for post message
tracker but I think it would be really
cool to to add a a line that that shows
every time a post message tracker is
registered and where it's registered so
so you you know just like you get a
request where you know you get a log in
your console when it gets sent through
um when a post message is sent through
you can also get a log when one is
registered so you can know okay well the
you know
my uh child Windows third if frame has
registered a launch a listener that that
could be really cool because that attack
surface is all over the place like you
mentioned absolutely and and I would say
the most common ones I found nowadays
are the ones not initiated from from
start but by action yeah so they they
just because you so I have an example in
one talk I did on in Amsterdam for like
a live hacking event basically what
happened was that when you clicked on
upload document there was a listener
started at that action and then you
could do whatever you could basically
read whatever document you uploaded you
could read it from the sandbox uh but
but so there's a bunch of those like
action-based listeners that gets
triggered by things and what I've seen
late like lately also and I think one of
the biggest tricks that up my sleeve
with the post message listener was the
unpacking of the wrappers yeah uh so
basically everything is wrapped through
New New Relic or roll bar or there's a
bunch of those but and jQuery also has
its own wrapper but the way of figuring
out how to bypass the wrapper and then
go directly to the function so you can
get like the real function that is
actually being triggered that was I
think the the Golden Nugget in in the
extension that is that that was really
helpful and what I've seen lately now is
like people using message ports which is
like an addition to to post message
where you send an initial post message
with a port and that Port can then be
you know you can Shuffle that Port
between if frames uh but the one having
the port is the one getting the messages
yeah dude I'm so glad you mentioned that
cuz I just found my first you know bug
using message ports in a live hacking
event maybe well I won't say exactly
when cuz because that'll give it away
but but within the past year right um
and and it was uh it was very
interesting and I think one of the
things that that was crazy there is it
it sometimes people will just get a port
and then they'll just shove data into it
without doing you know or origin checks
or anything like that too and so you
know it actually even creates more
complexity and more room for
vulnerabilities when when you're Iz in
the message Port stuff yeah and it's fun
because you can you can have a message
Port from one little ey frame and if you
get hold of that message Port you can
take it into a different iframe and then
the the the window thinking it sends
sends it to the if frame it's actually
sending it cross domain somewhere else
so that message Port can be you can
juggle that message Port wherever you
want which is kind of funny that it's
like just a connection it's basically
like a a socket that you can that
Shuffles it's I'm also kind of surprised
that we haven't seen more post message
based tooling out there like maybe I'm
just naive but your post message tracker
is pretty much the only extension that
I've seen that that does anything like
this so um one thanks for doing that
because otherwise you would have no
introspection I use it I use it every
day myself it's my the only probably
extension I use myself and every every
day I'm looking at it so it's like I'm
that it's a good example of like writing
something that would you would use
yourself yeah and it's 100% like that
like it doesn't go a day without me
looking at I I kind of like also to just
to highlight you
know the importance of understanding
browser mechanics and stuff like that so
let's say for example you you you know
post message stuff was just coming out
or something like that right and you go
to a page and you see a an ifame open up
or or not an if frame a popup you know
open
up and it does something and then it re
you know that change somehow seems to
appear back on the on the original
window right and you don't see any HTTP
request so it's not pushing out to the
server and not coming back right so
you're like wait a second how the heck
is this working because if you have a an
understanding of browser mechanics you
you know you need you need some sort of
reference to pass it and that sort of
thing same origin kind of works still
yeah same origin is fine for that yeah
so it's it's important to understand you
know if it's happening cross orig like
that you can't just you know say parent
you know or opener dot you know window
you know whatever and just Define
variables or trigger callbacks in the
parent window if it's cross origin so so
having the a strong understanding of
same origin policy having a strong um
understanding of of um window references
you know that those sort of things are
essential to be able to identify these
sort of issues um for as the technology
evolves absolutely and I think I one one
thing that I I I did some talks on it
but I think
is there will be a lot more bugs on it
it's it's client side race conditions
with post message I I think that's I
think I was early on with it uh but I
think that there are much more places to
investigate that might be similarly
vulnerable to it I I don't uh so I've
got a couple client side race conditions
um in place um bugs that I found and I'm
actually doing some research on them
right now uh which I'll share with you
after this after this chat um and maybe
we can collab on it because uh the
implications of it are pretty gnarly um
but uh it's I need to do what you did
with uh oh 30 dancing and just like you
know work through all the all the
pathways work with all the pathways to
it but yeah I mean there there's so many
things that can be said about that one
piece that is not super relevant to the
to the um to the bug that the or to the
research that I'm talking about is the
the concept of client side race
conditions via post message when um one
of the people is using json.parse
so the thing about json.parse is that it
it when you're parsing that that Json
data from a string back into a Json
object that takes
computational power to to load up all
those objects right so I had a scenario
when I was getting a post message at two
different windows at the same time right
and I needed to so this window was relay
the first window that would receive the
post message was relaying it to me the
attacker but then that first window
would respond to the post message and
set some configuration settings right so
I had to receive it you needed the
message to be first but you also needed
to read it faster than the other exactly
so the F the first window that received
it was using Json pars yeah string
matching I guess exactly I used I used
just substring right to extract this
this variable that I needed to
m a little TI those things are are
beautiful Json pars is a little bit um
computationally also also I think like
the whole concept of sending uh object
like arbitrary objects I know F scriptor
made one of those using blob yeah uh but
there there are a bunch like you can
send the RX object uh and and so there's
a bunch of these like if this is not a
string kind of bugs that you can find
just because you're sending a completely
different object with post message uh I
think it's like file blob regex there's
a bunch of more that you can uh you can
send over wow I didn't know that
actually I got to look into that and I
know that some some providers have
implemented Frameworks where like
serialization and D serialization
Frameworks that just make my life
terrible they are crazy I know know
exactly what you mean I've seen those as
well it takes a lot lot of time but
sometimes in those cases I I rather look
for the the syns first exactly or like
like is is it even you
know time to go down this path yeah
exactly no totally those are tricky I
agree wow um all right moving along I'm
gonna I'm gonna hit this next one pretty
quickly but I will say for any of you
that are are aspiring to be live hacking
event participant
uh this talk by by frons live hacking
like an MBH a walk through on
methodology and strategies to win big uh
is an amazing talk that talks about the
live hacking event experience and how to
do well at live hacking events um so we
talk about a lot of this stuff as well
also let me just say uh as of this past
Vegas I have been uh what is it deeded
unseed as the as tied for the most mvhs
and now fron has taken back his right
title as um you know MBH master of sorts
so I will get that back fron give me
some time at some point at some point I
guess uh but this this you know this
talk goes through
essentially the live hacking event flow
and and actually some of the OG live
hacking event flow where you would like
you know have to use Bounty please which
is a a uh tool that FR wrote to
automatically submit all your bugs in
the beginning what a crazy time man
where you would just not where you would
like get if you didn't get your bug in
fast enough it was just there was no
Bounty like what the heck no exactly I
think I think it was also you got duped
because if someone posted it before you
didn't have a dup window basically yeah
it's crazy so yeah it was It was kind of
weird it like incentivized building
those toolings uh for sure but I know
people I I think there have been live
hacking events lately also did like that
needed to get in things quick so i' I've
gotten requests to like like reignite
that project man because like and and I
think it's also to be honest because a
lot of people tend to write markdown
reports themselves first and then trying
to like get it in squeeze it into the
the the Bounty platform so for those of
you that my favorite part about Bounty
please by the way is that it's all
written in bash yeah okay yeah I love
bash damn I write everything in bash
yeah so I I was gonna ask that same
question Joel like dude why do you write
everything in bash like like pipelines
man you can it's like a functional
functional language because you can pipe
everything through everything like it's
it's like that's where
python python script into some other
python I mean sure but but now you like
your whole script is based on piping
data through you know conversions and
and things so I think I think it's just
uh my mentality is not like this is a
script and this is a pipeline with the
script it's more like my script is my
pipeline or often I think it's like an
organic thing of like my my my script is
becoming it's becoming a script because
I used a pipeline and now I'm like so I
think it's just my mentality of like
that's and I think I I tend to use it so
much also because it's like it's goes so
fast on building it yeah uh you know we
we we'll roll away we'll we'll let you
we'll let that fly let that slide no
worries um and and we'll I wanted to
talk to you about collaboration in live
hacking events and I want to read a
quote from um the the this article and
you give a lot of great advice uh in
this article or in this um in this slide
deck about um essentially doing the work
that other people aren't willing to do
um focusing on the boring stuff and and
you know configuring all the things that
other hackers won't configure that's the
way to get the big bounties and the way
to hit hit sort of untapped attack
surface and that's great so I wanted to
shout that out but I also wanted to talk
about this section where you said uh you
were talking about teaming because
teaming is something that we talk about
on critical thinking a lot Joel and I
Joel is one of the the few people um
actually one of the only people I think
that I have ever done s in my opinion
successfully done a a collaboration with
over the past five years where it was a
full from the beginning to the end
collaboration right yeah um and I think
that's because I've been burned a little
bit in the past on large teams um and
that and that that is what it is
everyone needs to have that learning
experience but I get a little bit of a
bad rap for being anti- collaboration
now I'm not anti- collaboration by any
stretch um but you give some really
great advice here so let me read that
with regards to teaming team up with
someone that one will put similar effort
into as you two might know stuff you
don't three helps you cover more attack
surface four you can communicate with
and brain stream or brainstream uh
brainstorm and then you say both right
exactly uh if you look at uh freaking
matias's DMS it might be seem more of a
brain stream than a
brainstorm I mean it makes sense brain
stream also um and then you say keep
keep teams small two to four if three or
more effort will differ allow splitting
differently for two people 50% is always
the simplest so that was sort of like
the brain dump of of collaboration
wisdom you did back in the day do you
still hold to all that absolutely 100% I
think and I I think it's very
interesting also in terms of like where
uh when like I do try to collaborate
with new people all the time um and and
you know once or twice sometimes maybe
around one bug and sometimes maybe you
know during an event or during just a
Target sometimes even and I always come
to the conclusion that it's like a lot
easier to do it two people uh because
then it's it's much easier to you know
it's very simple than if if both are
collaborating then then the full team is
there but if you're three maybe two of
them are working together one night the
other one can't and like it's it it just
after two it becomes like really hard to
align that everybody's doing equal work
because you do you don't want to get end
up in like me personally would not like
to end up in the in the scenario where I
get paid for doing
nothing uh and I hope that other people
don't feel great about that either it's
like because I wouldn't I I I sometimes
feel bad with one person when that
person is providing much more than I do
uh but I I at least try to put in the
time trying to find things uh but so I I
struggle a lot with h you know often
with like I'm like I don't need to be
collaborator on this thing because I
didn't do anything that kind of
mentality uh myself so I really like I
enjoy people having the same kind of
mentality themselves uh and you quite
quickly notice the ones that don't
really care and like almost gets to you
know ride on a sandwich it's a Swedish
proverb but but like uh gets gets to do
things are getting paid for not do what
the kind of proverb is that right on a
sandwich r on a sandwich actually it's
actually ride on the shrimp sandwich
what the freak yeah yeah yeah it's like
yeah I don't I yeah it's weird but yeah
so it's I and and so that's why like
when you identify the people that like
kind of align with you on those things
it becomes so much easier to like
collaborate and like just focus on the
fun stuff which is the hacking part and
and try to you know find the best way uh
to escalate the [__] yeah I mean that's
one of the things I really love about
live hacking events is that I find that
more often than not any random person at
a live hacking event that I walk up to
I'm able to almost like jump the line
and get to a communication level that
like it's very hard to establish with
other people just out of out of the gate
and part of that I think is just that
like we all have a similar kind of
technical background we all have a very
common like base of knowledge about like
web security or just even just Security
in general and like the types of bugs
and stuff and if you can get past that
and just start talking immediately about
like technical problems and being on the
same page it helps so much with actually
making progress with bugs I see this all
the time with me and Justin uh co-ack
essentially where we'll sit down at a
live hacking event and maybe one of us
will drive and the other one's just
really just like sitting there like
looking like seeing and like the
communication like we don't even speak
in sentences it's just like what he'll
be like oh that's really it'll be like
yeah I mean have we tried doing like and
and we don't even like we kind of just
like we're looking at the same thing
we're consuming the same thing we can
kind of jump through communication and
almost in shortcuts um and I really love
being able to do that when you get to
like more and more people that starts to
fall apart and it becomes less scalable
I think probably the most you can do
that with is maybe like four people
where you have four people like sort of
huddled around like throwing ideas
before you start to run into
communication problems not not even just
like the the like barrier to to
communication but just like too many
people are talking at the same time or
like there's too many ideas running
around there or there's too many
perspectives where it's like we're not
you know like we're never really going
down a full path because somebody you
know if three people think one thing and
the other person is like ah but like you
know what about this thing and then you
get sidetracked so it definitely does
work best with with two I think yeah for
sure and I I the one the the times we've
been for it has naturally become you
know pairs uh so you have to to that is
like very much fine and we've had done
we have done some live hacking events
for people but sometimes in those like
you sometimes also like you need to be
prepared to have like very tough
discussion like if it goes well you need
to have tough discussions on like hey
guys me and you know X put in a little
bit more time than you guys I are you
all like fine with us you know getting a
larger percentage of whatever it is and
and those kind of discussions and if you
can't have those or if they turn you
know ugly then it's going to be a really
hard time to to to collaborate in the
future but if you can have those great
ones then it doesn't you know the reason
the reason I bring this topic up often
on the podcast is because I want people
to be aware of the fact that there there
are some sticky situations you can get
into with this right absolutely and so
anyone going into collaboration needs to
know that there is risk and there's
reward um and and you need to be ready
to have these these conversations and
here's the other thing a lot of people
will take the high road and say like you
know it's it's it's just money you know
it's not a big deal but I found that
those people will Harbor
resentment they they'll they'll leave
that that that resentment in their heart
right and that that's not that's not
sometimes without knowing exactly
sometimes without knowing and that
that's not helpful for the community you
know and and so no I think I I I think
it's absolutely important to like if you
can feel that you dare to have that
discussions with the people you
collaborate with that's a really good
situation to be in because if you feel
that you can't take that up uh then
maybe you should I don't know then it
then it becomes like if you if you feel
that like I will put that back even
personally like I will avoid not saying
anything even though I feel bad like as
you said like you would feel bad going
forward like it's much better to like
ease it up and say like hey guys like I
I put in a lot of time in this and so
did he or something can we do something
about it and let them you know see where
they are what they are suggesting or you
know maybe they are saying yeah we 100%
agree then okay then you have then you
you can align that and then everybody's
happy um these problem you don't really
have these problems when uh when you
don't find B though that's true like
these are these are like the Happy
problems yeah it's good problems to have
and and it's really good to train
yourself to have those discussions
because you might get stepped on if not
and that's not a great feeling to have
either so um so I know some people are
like trying to measure how much work
they put in compared to each other and
stuff but I don't I don't think that's
uh that's a a good way either it's just
going to get dirty but but I I think
it's it's all around finding the people
that you know are putting in the time
that you and you need to try right you
need to try with with people and and
collaborate and sometimes you find those
matches like me and shs hadn't
collaborated but we did last year for my
first time and and like after that we've
been collaborating maybe once a month
sometimes more and it's like it's so
easy to do it together we're like and
also like him him in Australia like I
have a bug I go to bed I I write to him
before I go to bed like this is what I
found I wake up and he like oh I found
it I was like but like uh this is Magic
like this is such a good collaboration
and and turn in turn a high into a crit
just because like he found something I
didn't and that's just the power of
collaboration me Matias does that every
single day so it's it's such a such a
great thing to uh to be able to utilize
yeah yeah I love that about
collaborating like often when I find
somebody who's who I collaborate with
really well together it's not like um
it's not so much like I I don't really
think about who's found what bug or like
H how should this be balanced it's like
usually if it's going really well it's
that we're both frustrated about like
the same things and maybe like one
person finds something that's really
critical uh but it's it's never like
just like by themselves like in a corner
like you two have both been putting in
like a lot of the same amount of brain
effort and for me that's what really
matters is like like what you said in
your slide is like find somebody who um
contributes like a similar amount of uh
of like effort and and you know time and
that kind of stuff because it's not
really like how many bugs they're
finding it's like are you on the same
page are you both engaged at the same
level like does it feel like we're both
putting in the same amount of energy
because that combined energy will get
satisfying outputs for both people even
if you didn't like find the exact
payload or whatever like you were there
the whole time yes yeah exactly that's
exactly 100% that and also like I think
with with the whole collaboration thing
uh I mean sometimes it's it's like the
the wins you do together is it's like
they last much longer than winning
yourself like they do and it's not it's
absolutely not only money mattering like
it's it's actually like we did this
together we we we we spent this time to
like we we we did all these things and
that win is like so much bigger than
than doing yeah for sure I you know Joel
that the one of the most um foremost
times that that we collaborated together
that we did a full a full split collab
that is that is one of my favorite live
hacking events I've ever done and my I
think I was asked recently in an
interview what's your favorite hacking
memory the the time that shell popped
was my my favorite hacking memory so
absolutely I think I remembered this EV
hon um yeah you guys were similarly
[Laughter]
tired okay so um I want so the
middleware everywhere and lots of
misconfigurations to fix blog post
phenomenal I I think we're going to skip
it for now um we talked a little bit
about it in the you know when we were
talking about the service worker stuff
and we're going to jump right to um
account hijacking using Dirty Dancing
and sign in O flows want to get in some
technical details here first I just got
to
say I love this concept of breaking the
state intentionally right in in the oath
flow um could you give us a talk a
little bit about that technique and why
that's so helpful cuz I freaking love it
yeah so to be honest when I found that
that it was a technique I kind of like
yeah obviously it is uh but I also
realized like there is not that many
things uh other than the post message
that would be relevant for doing that or
doing so because there's not that much
things other than post message today
that might leak your full URL so the
whole thing with with oath breaking the
state intention is basically that you
often have this state parameter where
combined with the code that you're
getting back and the whole idea with the
state parameter is is that it's first
initiated by the website that you're
trying to sign into and then the state
parameter basically just gets sent
through the the the O St and then comes
back identical to what you send send it
the the website sent it as and if it's
matching then it will go through the O
flow so it's it's a fully the the whole
mitigation Factor here is that if if the
website itself decides on a state
specifically for this uh user it can set
the cookie or whatever to make sure that
it's the same state that comes back it's
actually a mitigation to prevent you
know uh somebody to send you a link and
and get get you to to connect to their
attacker account or you know a bunch of
other sea surfish uh attacks with with
oos uh but the funny thing is that the
whole implementation of validating the
state is happening before you acquire
the code which is like the best thing
for the attacker if you can leak through
your url if you can get the victim to
use your your state instead because then
you can just take everything the code
will never be used because the
validation of state is before and and
then and then you can take it and rerun
the same code and you know the original
state because you generated the original
state yeah yeah yeah I regenerated it
and send it to the victim concept here
is you've got an attacker he's
positioned in such a way that he can
redirect the victim somewhere so or send
the link to it send the link to them
send the link and and um so they they
generate an oath flow URL that has a
state that only the attacker knows right
and he gives it a different state to the
victim and when the victim goes through
and and tries to even maybe use exchange
that code plus the state for an an O
token once it bounces back from the O
provider that that will fail because the
state does not match the internal state
but and then the code is just sitting in
the fragment and then you can go and get
that code and exchange that code plus
the state that you know for the and I've
actually seen some scenarios with this
where when the ooth flow fails it will
redirect to a different location right
and and that can expose you start sit
for ex exactly that can expose that data
to more to more risks which is yes so
yeah and and the the the funny part with
the whole state thing is also like you
don't often times you don't because
there's a difference between if you get
a code back in O flow you need to get
the code to convert into an access token
and and most often you need to provide
what redirect URI that was being used
and if that redirect is differing from
the redirect URI that was actually being
used in the a St you might not get the
access token but breaking the state is
like you're ending up on the correct
redirect U it's there's like that
validation is just like completely
avoided because the same redirect URI
you will end up on the same correct
Place uh and and but but the state is
the only thing that's breaking it
awesome so it's it's actually like one
of the reasons why some of the parts are
automatable when it comes to Dirty
Dancing gadgets and things because what
you can do is like you can figure out if
there are listeners when you're
intentionally me like changing the state
in a l flow if there are listeners
somewhere in that you know coming back
on the error page you can like easily
figure out that something is that's
that's aw is there for investigation
yeah so you know we talked about the ups
and downs of of doing the research in
this article which is phenomenal the
other piece that I wanted to talk about
was subbing the the response type that
to
tokenid token or or ID token versus code
and how that affects how the redirect
URI is used could you talk a little bit
about that
sure I mean the the concept I found was
that there are certain transfer
mechanisms that the oath uh
specification tells you to use depending
on what type of data uh the oath
provider is sending back to the website
what that means is basically like for
example if you use uh um if you want to
get back an access token the access
token is never supposed to be sent as a
query parameter it's actually supposed
to be sent as a fragment part of the URL
and the reason for that is basically
that it doesn't show up in Access logs
on the website um you can still reach it
with JavaScript so the website can still
get it but it's not leaked to access
logs or anything the fragment stays on
the client side and it's client side
script that needs to fetch it uh same
thing happens with ID token ID token is
like a little bit in little bit in
between but it tends to be more on the
fragment side than
than on the on the query parameter side
but in addition to this you have
response modes and some of the response
modes will fail if you try if you try
for example to get like a a token and
you have a response mode query sometimes
response mode
query is is a thing then you should be
should getting an error you should you
you can get it through either through
fragment or uh it's called Web post or
web message I think uh which is like
actually sending data over through post
message it all depends on the on the
oath provider what they've decided on
being the response modes Apple made up
them their own uh there's also one
called form post where it's posting
submitting the the access token as as a
post request to the website and that one
is I think I mentioned it in the end as
a potential exploitation Factor because
uh Google has even though you have like
really locked up redirect U on on Google
uh you can still enable a mode uh with
parameters that tells you that it should
post uh post the the data as as a post
request but then you can select whatever
URL on the website you want even
subdomains what uh so that one is is
ripe for exploitation I think that one
is not supposed to work as it should uh
I mentioned it because I wanted it to be
fixed and I think I I do still think
it's possible to to utilize it the thing
I found with it though it's like it's
really there you can talk about stars
being in line because you need something
that either reflects post data uh in a
way that you can read it somewhere else
through post message or whatever so
because post data you can't re reach
with JavaScript unless you reflect it uh
the other thing you might be able to do
is like is there somewhere on this
domain where you can get the post data
to be read and IAL with one of the team
in Google and he said on Google there is
one so you have script.google.com which
is like a script Gadget there you can
have a URL that can receive a post
request and you can read the logs of it
that's that's basically but but they
don't have OAS danc on their own website
so Google don't don't have it for Google
uh I haven't found an exploit
exploitable
place that can be used to submit the
post request where you can later on I
got to go reread that because that
section seems so interesting Joel I know
that this episode has gone long do you
have to bounce right now I do have to
bounce so I don't want to cut this short
but I'm GNA let you I'm gonna have to
hop on and listen to the rest of this
rest this uh you know a lot stuff but
yeah we'll definitely we'll talk about
about this more um and you can go back
and review it afterwards because there's
going to be some good stuff here I can
tell already so peace Joel but yeah it
it was awesome talk talking with you and
hopefully you guys have a good rest of
your conversation um yeah no that that
sounds nuts and and I think playing with
those different types is is really
something that I haven't played around
with too much um and something that I
want to I want to look into because the
the impact of that is is massive too if
you are able to leak those in any
capacity one thing that I was thinking
about for the Post message thing is like
it's very rare but if you could find a
307 open redirect as well yeah you could
hit exactly they would move it it's
extremely rare uh but it might be like
misconfigurations in their you know load
balancer kind of things but it 307s are
hard I'm I'm I'm I'm collecting 307s man
they're hard find if you do that or or
you know like well I guess most of the
time yeah n because you couldn't really
do it with a um with a crlf either you'd
really need
yeah you really need a
307 it's It's Tricky man it is it's
super hard that's so so um the redirect
so you said sometimes different response
types will have different places that
they can redirect to that's some like is
is that accurate or no
um I mean that I would say that one is
an exception especially for Google uh I
I would say that they
are in some sense you're right because
what happens with the web message or the
post message uh response type or
response mode is that then any page on
that or because it needs to normalize
the origin right so the origin turns
into the domain and that means that any
page on on that origin can read the
message sent by post message so in a
sense yes the redirect Ur will change in
that sense because it will just be any
any page on the or in getting that
message I'm not I'm not fully wrapping
my I don't think so but there you also
have an attack Vector because there is a
bunch of post message listeners that
works as proxis uh what happens is that
when they get a message they will relay
that message to an iframe for example so
if you can chain the the oath web uh the
oath web message posting a message to
one of those relays uh that just relays
it to another iframe and then you can
find something on that origin of the
iframe then you can uh then you can also
find like that's another sort of Gadget
you could say um but you still need to
find something maybe it's a sun like the
Reddit bug I had I saw that one quite
similar yeah so the Reddit bug was
basically that the they used window name
to transfer data over to their sandbox
uh and the sandbox had a bunch of xss
people knew about it like long before or
you could literally run your own Google
analytics on it uh so if I ran my Google
no Google tag manager and if I ran my
own Google time manager I could run
script on the sandbox uh but but because
they named the window with the payload
the the payload was transferred down
through window name and then you can
read the fragment through window name
yeah I we mentioned a different one uh a
bug sort of similar to that um there was
a report that came out on pixiv uh
hacker one program which is uh
essentially the vulnerability was the
the app allows you to specify your own
Google analytics token and and if you
can do that then you can leak all sorts
of stuff and and with that you could
redirect um the aoth code to that a page
that was using that Google analytics
token which would allow you to to leak
the content so there's all sorts of ways
through stats there's all sorts of ways
that you can access that um yeah and and
I think this one this account hijacking
via Dirty Dan one I I it's it's a very
long one like you've mentioned you know
there's you like to do long write ups
but this is something I'm going to go
ahead and reread after this EP after
this episode again because there's so
many pieces to this where um I mean the
the out of bound things there there
there's so many things that I've
forgotten like that that's not even it
to be honest it's not even post message
like imagine imagine just having a
Tracker service or something that you
can leak that that has some form of API
somewhere else that you can leak dat so
the the the the outof band Gadget is
like there's huge potential for research
there because what happens if you break
the state for example you end up on the
page it sends it over to tracking
service X and Y but that tracking
service has some form of you know
history or whatever not through post
message or anything but you can you can
just utilize the same API key or
whatever like there's so many things
there that lot of application Level
stuff as well you know that you can use
just because that that one could be sent
so deep into something else somewhere
somewhere and you can pick it up those
are the nice ones where you like you
sent the victim over there it does a
bunch of things and then you're sitting
here pulling an API and suddenly it
shows up a API you know a code or an
exess token and you can steal it from
there those are the most kind of in the
way you describe it as well beautiful
that that that even shows a little bit
more to the fact that um you know these
things they take so much art you know
they and and it kind of goes back to
what we were talking about earlier of
like I want to find a bug that I'm proud
of and sometimes that takes time you
know and so spending time looking at
applications like you said sometimes
it's three days three or four days
before you find a bug yeah and and some
I think a lot of people newer to the
industry would really stress out about
that but if you put in the time and you
really understand all of The Fringe
application logic then you start to be
able to chain together crazy stuff like
leaking o tokens via application fun fun
that you know log stuff so it's
definitely cool to see um last section
that I wanted to talk about before I I
let you go do you have time I know we're
over time okay sure sure was hacking
plus Parenthood so I I I wanted to so
you know you mentioned before sometimes
you got a week a week and a half and
then you never know what that's going to
look like with kids um yeah you know I'm
I'm thinking about starting a family
soon and I'm a little bit worried about
what it's going to look like to do full
10 Buck bounty and have kids around do
you do you normally hack from your home
do you normally hack from the office do
you have any general advice about bug
Bounty with kids I know that that's a
broad question but yeah it's a broad
question it depends on the age of the
kids I guess but I I would say like this
uh I I had I was lucky with my first kid
being a really good sleeper that's
awesome but so that helped me that
helped me hacking a lot during nights H
that that was also in the in the time
where was like almost addicted to it so
I really had to I wanted to put in that
time and I invested almost like sleep
hours just because I I I was like almost
yeah monomania kind of thing uh but but
then I think with my my second kid which
was not such a great sleeper I kind of
came to to the point where I'm like that
was also where when I was working all
like working bug hunting and having two
kids and then I like I had to remove
something door no no that what the work
went out the door actually so H because
I I I felt that like I really want to
continue doing hacking and uh kids are
going stay um but but so I I think one
of the one of the aspects of it was
that it helped me like what what
happened then was that I replaced my
working hours with hacking hours which
has always been like I've been scared
about it because I felt like the
funniest bugs I find is always 3:00 a.m.
like that has been a mantra to me that
that's the way it is because my minds
work in in in you know in a weird way
during during nights uh so so but but
that has kind of shifted now when I'm
going deep diving and because it's you
know you're spending like five days on
one specific functionality it doesn't
really matter if it's happening on night
and day because you're getting into that
zone regardless during during those like
there's some maturing that's happening
here you know
likeably you know in the beginning I I
very much had the same experience where
I was like wow I'm very addicted to this
and I would easily say okay let me not
go to bed and let me go and hack you
know and and I feel like that was pretty
pretty and it did get great results but
I think it was unsustainable for me in
some capacity yes and so I think as as
you kind of grow as a bug Bounty Hunter
and and you figure out you know hey
maybe there are different options for
this it becomes a little bit more
sustainable would you would you agree
with that yes yeah I agree and I think
to be honest like I still have these
thing where I'm like oh I I need to
continue this but what I've realized
also is like the worst thing that can
happen is that I stop hacking at the
time where I don't have anything to
continue with uh that's that's feeling
the worst because ites it really to
start doing it again because you're like
where should I go where should I go so I
realized like the best way the best
place I am is where I'm like oh my God
and then I'm like closing down the
computer and I'm like oh that like the
day after I will wake up the earliest I
will go like do all the chores
everything and then I go back to it
compared to like I'm empty now D what an
amazing tip that is that is something
that I've never out of all the you said
this this time I feel like this little
tidbit is kind of crazy because like
that's so counterintuitive to me like no
I I wouldn't want to give up right as
I'm or like stop right as I'm about to
find something but if you do you're so
motivated to come back and everything
else just kind of seems to it becomes so
much easier to do like the chores or the
waking up early because as soon as your
eyes open in the morning you're like
wait I got to I got to try it you know
and so that's that's amazing and then
you you get like so I I really want to I
always want to find the place where I'm
like oh I I mean I understand like if
you're in the middle of like popping a
shell like oh yeah plus there's dupes
and stuff like that too you know yeah
but suddenly like you see an error
message that stands out or something
like like oo like that's when I close my
computer that that's when because I'm
like okay I have something for tomorrow
it's it's almost like it's night here I
I will focus on something else but there
is something here and I have a huge
attack surface tomorrow that I can you
know H squeeze and and Fiddle around
with uh but but so that it's a it's a
very short amount of time where I have
the ability to like stop doing it
because I can continue and I will get to
a point where I'm like it's 5:00 a.m.
and I'm gonna you know take the kids to
school and and I'm going to be terrible
tomorrow and I've been there 100 times
but I'm I've realized also like it it
takes time to realize that okay I have a
short time span here when I'm like okay
I can get good amount of sleep uh but I
will have some really fun days tomorrow
or Fun hours tomorrow to play with
duding it's it it takes it takes it
takes practice and it takes self control
and it takes discipline you know and and
yeah for sure like there the longer and
longer I'm in this in Industry you you
kind of see how all this sort of becomes
an art um you know managing your your
creativity and your and your um you know
it's to guess yeah and and and so any
any techniques like this which can allow
you to maintain that
creative um that Creative Energy that
creative motivation very important I
think France dude this has been an
amazing podcast thank you so much for
coming on here and sharing all the
wisdom which you've had over the over
the over the years of of doing bug
Bounty do you have any anything you want
to shout out or any socials you want us
to advertise at the end of
this no oh I mean shout out to my to my
collaborators that I often collaborate
with shs of Brun um Frederick sitting in
the office behind me
um I'm having fun Peter as well a new
collaborator I haven't done anything P4
dude awesome um that was that was uh a
great SC we're trying we're always you
know poking at each other I'm going to
stop you there because I I know I know
I have so many I can experience of like
um you know you're trying to think about
like I got to think of all these people
I'm sure there are many more you could
list but um yeah fron Rosen everybody uh
you can find them at Twitter pretty much
everywhere as fron Rosen just write out
the name and then definitely what we're
going to link down in the description
all the detectify blogs and stuff like
that which contain all the awesome
content from uh this episode in in more
depth so fron thank you so much man
thank you thank you bye